<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>NoConformity</title>
  <subtitle>A free spirited, sex positive, polish internet brick laying capitalist.</subtitle>
  <id>http://noconformity.com</id>
  <link href="http://noconformity.com/"/>
  <link href="http://noconformity.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2014-09-12T13:31:00-07:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Chris Hough</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Jekyll Is Slower Than A Snail</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/2014/09/12/jekyll-is-slower-than-a-snail/"/>
    <id>/2014/09/12/jekyll-is-slower-than-a-snail/</id>
    <published>2014-09-12T13:31:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2014-09-12T13:31:00-07:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Hough</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It has been awhile since my last post, but I am happy to report I’m finally back.  Both the day gig and night gig have been keeping me extremely busy, and on top of that I was mining out time to convert my blog to Middleman.  So why did I convert?...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It has been awhile since my last post, but I am happy to report I’m finally back.  Both the day gig and night gig have been keeping me extremely busy, and on top of that I was mining out time to convert my blog to Middleman.  So why did I convert? Ultimately Jekyll is not only a bit inflexible, it is beyond slow.  Let me say that again, IT IS BEYOND SLOW.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/images/posts/JekyllToMiddleman-d035040e.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I've built many websites utilizing Jekyll and all of them started to crawl during generation after 20 posts were in the system.  I took some time to research what other web geeks  were saying on this issue to see if any solutions have been proposed. Everywhere I researched, I found the same complaints. It just starts slowing down and there is nothing you could do to speed it up. Not only is the engine incapable of regenerating differential changes, but the limited development versus production modes make it hard to get around.  Also, the LSI post indexer, which attempts to compile related posts, makes things even worse. Today, there are a ton of newer &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://staticsitegenerators.net/"&gt;static site generators&lt;/a&gt; on the market to choose from. Being a rubyist, I wanted to stick with the language I’m working in on a regular basis. I have decided to try Middleman as a replacement. So what is different?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the jump there are a few drastically different things in Middleman compared to Jekyll.  Middleman is  extremely flexible, but you are on your own to build various plugins you may need.  Middleman is not only for blogs but can be used to generate all sorts of static site needs such as single page javascript applications [Note: This was covered at &lt;a href="/2014/04/21/rails-conference-2014/"&gt;Rails Conference 2014&lt;/a&gt; this year via "&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.confreaks.com/videos/3341-railsconf-middleman-the-missing-view-in-the-rails-api-stack"&gt;Middleman: The missing front end of the Rails API stack by Brad Gessler&lt;/a&gt;"].  To get around the plug in issue you can simply create your own sets of ruby methods that can be accessed throughout your views. Pretty straight forward right? I created methods for post images, amazon links, and even extended the string class to adjust titlecase to work with words like “Car2Go.” You can see &lt;a target="_blank" href="https://github.com/chrishough/myblog/tree/master/lib/helpers"&gt;them here&lt;/a&gt;. If you have experience with rails you will see how easy it is to utilitize multiple layouts, the asset pipeline, and even pry during development. When I started using Jekyll, the goal was to kill wordpress.  While it was successful in doing that, the slowness and inflexibility drove me mad over a period of time. &lt;strong&gt;I can honestly say that Jekyll was preventing me from writing&lt;/strong&gt;.  At the end of the day if you are considering generators (which I would recommend) for your blog or editorial components of your business, check out Middleman.  It may take you a bit longer to get up and running, but in the long run you will find it easier to work in, It generates quickly during development, and will feel more native if you are used to rails.  If you need help getting things running, feel free to ping me on twitter.  Check out the various methods I have added &lt;a target="_blank" href="https://github.com/chrishough/myblog/tree/master/lib/helpers"&gt;in my blog repo&lt;/a&gt;, and I highly recommend you use this &lt;a target="_blank" href="https://github.com/ngs/middleman-blog-similar"&gt;blog article&lt;/a&gt; for a replacement to Jekyll’s LSI.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>I Care</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/2014/06/20/i-care/"/>
    <id>/2014/06/20/i-care/</id>
    <published>2014-06-20T00:00:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2014-06-20T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Hough</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;What is about some people that makes them care more than others? Whether it’s taking out the garbage, washing their car, building a stick fort for their kids, or groking the latest technology, they put all of their energy into their work.  The older...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;What is about some people that makes them care more than others? Whether it’s taking out the garbage, washing their car, building a stick fort for their kids, or groking the latest technology, they put all of their energy into their work.  The older I get, the less patience I have for people who half ass their work, or slack on what they build.  I guess you can say that I have a hard time getting along with those who punch a clock.  I have never believed in such a boring existence.  I just can’t comprehend it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I care&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;about my wife.  She is my best friend, and she keeps me level headed.  I question any relationship where the partner is not the companion’s best friend.  It’s usually a tell of deeper issues in the relationship.  My second brain has my back and I have hers.  When she let’s me off the leash, I will spring to destroy anything that may harm her.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I care&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;about what I work on.  This means I use tools like brakeman, rubocup, codeclimate, and simplecov to name a few to constantly evaluate my code. I use these tools are used in both personal and professional products.  What I produce means something to me. It doesn’t matter if I’m CEO of the company or it’s the gig that I enjoy working at for coin to live.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I care&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;about working remote.  I am sorry I will not work for free and I have no interest in working in your office.  I do not need a babysitter. I get my work done. I meet objectives and I love what I do.  There are numerous options out there to support having a fully cohesive organization with peeps scattered all over this wonderful planet.  I believe in it. This works for both design and coding.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I care&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;about my close friends and advisors.  I do not give out a seat at my table for free. You have to earn it.  My heart has been bruised enough to learn that those who just randomly dish out pieces of themselves are often the worst ones to let in.  You meet many people along the journey of your life and not everyone will make it to your final destination.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I care&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;about art and the creative thinkers.  Just because you downloaded that new shiny music application, it does not mean you know shit about EDM.  Art comes in many forms including the sexy beautiful naked form of our human bodies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I care&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;about the sex industry and sex workers.  Yes, I am an ally and I believe in supporting members of the industry.  Exploring your sexuality, enjoying the companionship of multiple partners whether in the comfort of your own home or the big screen is never something to be ashamed of.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I care&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;about being an atheist.  The Richard Dawkins series the “The root of all evil” pretty much sums it up for me.  I often ponder how much farther our civilization would be if the various fictional religious dogmas did not plague our entire planet.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I care&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;about helping others who are busting their ass every day just like me.  Nothing should come for free. To the hard workers kicking ass, taking names, and building their dreams at 2am every damn day, I salute you.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Rails Conference 2014 Re-Cap</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/2014/04/30/rails-conference-2014-re-cap/"/>
    <id>/2014/04/30/rails-conference-2014-re-cap/</id>
    <published>2014-04-30T00:00:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2014-04-30T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Hough</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;If you work in rails and do not attend Rails Conference, you’re doing it wrong!  This year the conference was in my home town of Chicago and I have to say with a few exceptions it exceeded my expectations.  The venue was in a perfect location downtown...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;If you work in rails and do not attend Rails Conference, you’re doing it wrong!  This year the conference was in my home town of Chicago and I have to say with a few exceptions it exceeded my expectations.  The venue was in a perfect location downtown, close to outstanding bars and dining hotspots, and the hotel accommodations were quite nice. Overall it was awesome!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have always been a huge fan and advocate for attending conferences throughout my career.  As a developer, it’s rare you find yourself in a situation surrounded by all Apple MacBook Pros, fellow entrepreneurs who are building their dreams, and speakers who are the builders of the products you love to use.  Both the talks and the lobby chats were priceless,  I was able to chat with various owners of the gems we use everyday and form new relationships with like minded geeks all over the world.  While these opinions are pretty much a given, here are some thoughts on my favorite talks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;First, I thought all of the keynotes were amazing, including @dhh’s on &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.confreaks.com/videos/3315-railsconf-keynote-writing-software"&gt;TDD&lt;/a&gt; and @farrahbostic's on &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.confreaks.com/videos/3336-railsconf-keynote-what-happens-to-everyone-when-everyone-learns-to-code"&gt;What Happens to Everyone, When Everyone Learns to Code&lt;/a&gt;. If you have not watched it, I encourage you to do so.  After the video, prior to formulating your final opinion read “&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://david.heinemeierhansson.com/2014/tdd-is-dead-long-live-testing.html"&gt;TDD is dead. Long live testing&lt;/a&gt;.”  Let me begin by stating I believe in testing, but I have always argued that the application code is more valuable then the testing code.  If you are adjusting your application code just to make sure tests are passing, that smells a little fishy to me.  Also, make sure your tests are actually testing what they should be, including your user interfaces, not merely status codes and other b.s. your users will not interact with.  It is better to have a well rounded test suite that takes longer to run, than one that merely fires off all green lights  but omits key tests. People who know me, know I am a huge fan of 37 Signals and their philosophies.  I was beyond stoked to get to meet their founders.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="w-gallery layout_tile size_m"&gt;&lt;div class="w-gallery-h"&gt;&lt;div class="w-gallery-tnails"&gt;&lt;div class="w-gallery-tnails-h"&gt;&lt;a class="w-gallery-tnail order_1" href="/assets/images/posts/RailsConference201437signals1-c36083b7.jpg" title="@Dhh"&gt;&lt;span class="w-gallery-tnail-h"&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/images/posts/RailsConference201437signals1-c36083b7.jpg" /&gt;&lt;span class="w-gallery-tnail-title"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="w-gallery-tnail order_2" href="/assets/images/posts/RailsConference201437signals2-c39831ec.jpg" title="@jasonfried"&gt;&lt;span class="w-gallery-tnail-h"&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/images/posts/RailsConference201437signals2-c39831ec.jpg" /&gt;&lt;span class="w-gallery-tnail-title"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="w-gallery-tnail order_3" href="/assets/images/posts/RailsConference2014jobs-37f14bb8.jpg" title="Are you learning to program ruby?"&gt;&lt;span class="w-gallery-tnail-h"&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/images/posts/RailsConference2014jobs-37f14bb8.jpg" /&gt;&lt;span class="w-gallery-tnail-title"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;While I will save the details of the SOA architecture we are building at PlaceWise Media for a future post, I enjoyed each of the talks surrounding APIs and foundational service orientated architectures.  Unfortunately, they also forced me to rethink exactly how we are approaching our configuration.  The discussions on Rack-AMQP and Engines were fascinating.  Our current platform supports 8 total http based services of various sizes, however, after this conference and detailed discussions this week we are changing direction completely to harness engines from day 1.  I know this sounds a bit monolithic, but if you’re tasked with decoupling from legacy dead languages such as coldfusion, I would really consider engines.  It is far easier to control the bleeding at the model level.   Outside of the enterprise talks, the talk on building the api first sparked a chat with my co-founder that led to a significant deviation in our architecture.  Instead of using Rails for the front end and integrating various js libraries on top of it, we are going to break the setup into an ember.js application hosted on s3 and rails api hosted on heroku starting in v1.  Beyond SOAs, I attended a few talks where I was able to use new tricks that same day.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;First, “Advanced aRel” encouraged me to rethink how I am interacting with the db.  Why write the t-sql directly? No shit right? It looks ugly, and I would rather just deal straight with object notation.  Every time I see a talk on Pry I have to attend.  The second major take away was presented in “Debugger Driven Development with Pry.”  Those of us using pry know about binding.pry but I never knew you could stack them in an application and navigate through them like breakpoints.  Also, you can run your rails application with “rescue rails s” and be immediately taken to the pry prompt if a bug occurs.  Some may say this time savings is trivial, but I disagree.  Anything we do to speed up our workflows saves us precious, limited time, especially over the course of a year.  Outside of just pure tech, the conference covered numerous management techniques and psychological challenges, including imposter syndrome.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“&lt;a target="_blank" href="https://speakerdeck.com/nmeans/you-are-not-an-impostor"&gt;You Are Not An Impostor&lt;/a&gt;” was a session that hit too close to home.  I grew up with a father who was a strict perfectionist and sadly I have internalized many of the phrases he used to say to me.  This in turn bleeds over into nearly everything I take on.  I never feel like something is built correctly, I always find issues with things I develop, and I am never satisfied with my performance.  In fact, I always feel like I am going to get fired.  Over the years I have found many coping mechanisms to deal with these feelings, but it will be a life long struggle.  Yes, I will be writing about this more this year, and I encourage you to take the &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://impostortest.nickol.as/"&gt;Clance Impostor Phenomenon Test&lt;/a&gt;.  I have already stated how awesome this conference was, but I want to add a few more things.  If you have not traveled to Chicago, I hope these following pictures not only get you hungry right now, but they encourage a visit.  The tech scene is blowing up there, the food will get you stuffed, and the cocktails will lay you down.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="w-gallery layout_tile size_m"&gt;&lt;div class="w-gallery-h"&gt;&lt;div class="w-gallery-tnails"&gt;&lt;div class="w-gallery-tnails-h"&gt;&lt;a class="w-gallery-tnail order_1" href="/assets/images/posts/RailsConference2014food1-c10a2c28.jpg" title="Hot Dougs"&gt;&lt;span class="w-gallery-tnail-h"&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/images/posts/RailsConference2014food1-c10a2c28.jpg" /&gt;&lt;span class="w-gallery-tnail-title"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="w-gallery-tnail order_2" href="/assets/images/posts/RailsConference2014food2-565838f4.jpg" title="Portillos"&gt;&lt;span class="w-gallery-tnail-h"&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/images/posts/RailsConference2014food2-565838f4.jpg" /&gt;&lt;span class="w-gallery-tnail-title"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="w-gallery-tnail order_3" href="/assets/images/posts/RailsConference2014food3-94121d31.jpg" title="Kumas Corner"&gt;&lt;span class="w-gallery-tnail-h"&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/images/posts/RailsConference2014food3-94121d31.jpg" /&gt;&lt;span class="w-gallery-tnail-title"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="w-gallery-tnail order_4" href="/assets/images/posts/RailsConference2014food4-cb4d0773.jpg" title="Portillos"&gt;&lt;span class="w-gallery-tnail-h"&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/images/posts/RailsConference2014food4-cb4d0773.jpg" /&gt;&lt;span class="w-gallery-tnail-title"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="w-gallery-tnail order_5" href="/assets/images/posts/RailsConference2014food5-c9f8933f.jpg" title="Uncle Julios"&gt;&lt;span class="w-gallery-tnail-h"&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/images/posts/RailsConference2014food5-c9f8933f.jpg" /&gt;&lt;span class="w-gallery-tnail-title"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="w-gallery-tnail order_5" href="/assets/images/posts/RailsConference2014food6-461f04b0.jpg" title="Ginos East"&gt;&lt;span class="w-gallery-tnail-h"&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/images/posts/RailsConference2014food6-461f04b0.jpg" /&gt;&lt;span class="w-gallery-tnail-title"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="w-gallery-tnail order_7" href="/assets/images/posts/RailsConference2014family1-054c0b81.jpg" title="John and Mary Hough : My Parents"&gt;&lt;span class="w-gallery-tnail-h"&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/images/posts/RailsConference2014family1-054c0b81.jpg" /&gt;&lt;span class="w-gallery-tnail-title"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="w-gallery-tnail order_8" href="/assets/images/posts/RailsConference2014family2-e542d372.jpg" title="Frat brother and rocker Ra"&gt;&lt;span class="w-gallery-tnail-h"&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/images/posts/RailsConference2014family2-e542d372.jpg" /&gt;&lt;span class="w-gallery-tnail-title"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="w-gallery-tnail order_9" href="/assets/images/posts/RailsConference2014family3-f581f273.jpg" title="College roommate and fellow rubyist Tim Tyrrell"&gt;&lt;span class="w-gallery-tnail-h"&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/images/posts/RailsConference2014family3-f581f273.jpg" /&gt;&lt;span class="w-gallery-tnail-title"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Rails Conference 2014</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/2014/04/21/rails-conference-2014/"/>
    <id>/2014/04/21/rails-conference-2014/</id>
    <published>2014-04-21T00:00:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2014-04-21T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Hough</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I started working in ruby on rails just over a year ago, and I was lucky enough to attend my first Rails Conference in my backyard of Portland, Oregon.&lt;!--more--&gt;People who know me, know I am a huge fan of &lt;a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/dhh"&gt;@dhh&lt;/a&gt; and the 37 Signals philosophy of building a business...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I started working in ruby on rails just over a year ago, and I was lucky enough to attend my first Rails Conference in my backyard of Portland, Oregon.&lt;!--more--&gt;People who know me, know I am a huge fan of &lt;a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/dhh"&gt;@dhh&lt;/a&gt; and the 37 Signals philosophy of building a business.  The opening day of the conference my buddy &lt;a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/tempelmeyer"&gt;@tempelmeyer&lt;/a&gt; and I arrived before anyone else was there, even the setup crew.  We walked into the main auditorium and camped the front row.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/images/posts/RailsConference2013Room-b375fdc4.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Little did we know that we were not supposed to be in there that early, and the staff thought we were part of the first 2 special rows.  Once we discovered this, I thought to myself... “Well fuck it!”  I have always wanted to see a headliner like this.  Just like waiting for concert tickets, if you put in the time and get there first, you get the best seats in the house.  We were lucky.  Later my friend &lt;a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/vosechu"&gt;@vosechu&lt;/a&gt; stopped by and asked us to hold the first two rows for his students as payment.  We gladly accepted the offer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The keynote was fucking priceless!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A year has gone by and I am happy to be back in my hometown of Chicago for my 2nd Rails Conference.  Over the course of last year, I have started the foundations of a service orientated architecture written in rails 4 for my day gig.  Although I will save the juicy details of this battle for another post, I will say it has &gt; 8 rails apis, built with chef + cap, running in the cloud, solr sidekiq, 100% test coverage, and soon to be postgres over sql server.  Outside of the day gig, at night I have launched multiple jekyllrb editorial sites 100% static hosted on S3 and the 0.1 release of the application my wife &lt;a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/kathrynhough"&gt;@kathrynhough&lt;/a&gt; and I are building.  So what is on deck for this year?  I am planning on hitting my favorite Chicago restaurants and my schedule is posted below.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Let’s meet up for beers, chat apis, or anything geek related.  I look forward to meeting everyone at the best  programming conference of the year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cheers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tue 4/22&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.confreaks.com/videos/3315-railsconf-keynote-writing-software"&gt;Morning Announcement and Opening Keynote by David Heinemeier Hansson&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.confreaks.com/videos/3316-railsconf-domain-driven-design-and-hexagonal-architecture-with-rails"&gt;Domain Driven Design and Hexagonal Architecture with Rails by Declan Whelan, Eric Roberts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.confreaks.com/videos/3322-railsconf-where-did-the-oo-go-views-should-be-objects-too"&gt;Where did the OO go? Views should be objects too! by Andrew Warner&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.confreaks.com/videos/3327-railsconf-make-an-event-of-it"&gt;Make an Event of It! by Jason Clark&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.confreaks.com/videos/3330-railsconf-rack-amqp-ditch-http-inside-soa"&gt;Rack-AMQP: Ditch HTTP inside SOA! by Josh Szmajda&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.confreaks.com/videos/3332-railsconf-advanced-arel-when-activerecord-just-isn-t-enough"&gt;Advanced aRel: When ActiveRecord Just Isn't Enough by Cameron Dutro&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.confreaks.com/videos/3336-railsconf-keynote-what-happens-to-everyone-when-everyone-learns-to-code"&gt;What Happens to Everyone, When Everyone Learns to Code? by Farrah Bostic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wed 4/23&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.confreaks.com/videos/3337-railsconf-keynote-10-years"&gt;Keynote by Yehuda Katz&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.confreaks.com/videos/3338-railsconf-biggish-data-with-rails-and-postgresql"&gt;Biggish Data With Rails and Postgresql by Starr Horne&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.confreaks.com/videos/3341-railsconf-middleman-the-missing-view-in-the-rails-api-stack"&gt;Middleman: The missing front end of the Rails API stack by Brad Gessler&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.confreaks.com/videos/3344-railsconf-refactoring-towards-component-based-rails-architectures"&gt;Refactoring towards Component-based Rails architectures by Stephan Hagemann&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.confreaks.com/videos/3347-railsconf-rails-as-an-soa-client"&gt;Rails as an SOA client by Pete Hodgson&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.confreaks.com/videos/3350-railsconf-service-oriented-authenication"&gt;Service Oriented Authentication by Jeremy Green&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.confreaks.com/videos/3353-railsconf-authorization-in-a-service-oriented-environment"&gt;Authorization in a Service-Oriented Environment by Alan Cohen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thu 4/24&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.confreaks.com/videos/3357-railsconf-keynote-humor-in-the-code-the-future-of-everything-humbly-stated"&gt;Keynote by Baratunde Thurston&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.confreaks.com/videos/3359-railsconf-designing-the-apis-for-an-internal-set-of-services"&gt;Designing the APIs for an internal set of services by Alberto Leal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.confreaks.com/videos/3362-railsconf-build-the-api-first"&gt;Build the API First by Rosie Hoyem, Sonja Hall&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.confreaks.com/videos/3365-railsconf-debugger-driven-developement-with-pry"&gt;Debugger Driven Development with Pry by Joel Turnbull&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.confreaks.com/videos/3368-railsconf-effectively-testing-services"&gt;Effectively Testing Services by Neal Kemp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.confreaks.com/videos/3371-railsconf-eliminating-inconsistent-test-failures"&gt;Eliminating Inconsistent Test Failures by Austin Putman&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fri 4/26&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.confreaks.com/videos/3374-railsconf-an-ode-to-17-databases-in-33-minutes"&gt;An Ode to 17 Databases in 33 minutes by Toby Hede&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.confreaks.com/videos/3380-railsconf-how-to-be-a-boss-without-the-b-s"&gt;How To Be a Boss without the B-S by Jessie Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.confreaks.com/videos/3383-railsconf-building-an-oss-centric-company-and-why-you-want-to"&gt;Building an OSS-Centric Company and Why You Want To by Leah Silber&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Unreasonable Estimates and Improbable Goals : Adam Sanderson&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.confreaks.com/videos/3387-railsconf-curmudgeon-an-opinionated-framework"&gt;Curmudgeon: An Opinionated Look at an Opinionated Framework by Ernie Miller&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.confreaks.com/videos/3392-railsconf-you-are-not-an-impostor"&gt;You Are Not An Impostor by Nickolas Means&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.confreaks.com/videos/3393-railsconf-closing-keynote"&gt;Keynote by Aaron Patterson&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Context Control</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/2014/04/15/context-control/"/>
    <id>/2014/04/15/context-control/</id>
    <published>2014-04-15T00:00:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2014-04-15T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Hough</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;If you are not paying for a service, you, the user, are in fact the product. Make no mistake about this.&lt;!--more--&gt;Everything from your likes, your photos, and basically your entire entity is owned by a corporation.  It took me a long time to come to this conclusion...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;If you are not paying for a service, you, the user, are in fact the product. Make no mistake about this.&lt;!--more--&gt;Everything from your likes, your photos, and basically your entire entity is owned by a corporation.  It took me a long time to come to this conclusion but basically I am saying fuck you to facebook. I’m done.  Today I closed my account. Was this a rash decision? No. I have been considering this for quite some time now.  One of my favorite sayings is “min-maxing constantly.”  If you do not know what that means, google it.  Over time I have started to wonder how much value various services and various connections in those services truly matter to me.  Would I invite each and every connection into my home for a private meal?  What really matters?  In life you only have so much time.  Time is the one thing as humans we all have in common, and I do not believe in wasting it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/images/posts/ByeByeFacebook-5f6be1d7.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I wrapped up the most recent rollouts to my business, I wanted to tackle my blog.  I wanted to regain full control of what was shared and who owned it.  At the same time, I have drastically cut down on the senseless noise around me.  Have you ever wondered how many of the loudest people are also the most unsuccessful?  Do I really give 2 shits about your dogs, your kids, people I will never see again except in passing?  Are single serving friends worth the extra effort? After dumping facebook, I completed a full purge across each my contacts.  Other services, such as LinkedIn, already direct traffic here.   Am I leaving all of social media? No. I have always enjoyed the interactions on twitter and especially instagram.  I tend to follow a broad spectrum of folks across many different industries.  The interactions feel more natural and are for more entertaining compared to the youtube like comments on facebook.  Hell, I met my wife through twitter.  At the end of the day, I think the communities are just plain different.  I have to admit, this inspiration did not just fall out of the damn sky.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A recent &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://thisweekinstartups.com/"&gt;This Week in Startups&lt;/a&gt; podcast with &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://thisweekinstartups.com/mark-cuban-kick-ass/"&gt;Marc Cuban&lt;/a&gt; covered the concept of controlling context. For the sake of simplicity, I will avoid going into a diatribe on how internet bullying is not only destructive but extremely dangerous to our society. I will mention that I have always been ok with pissing off others.  While I do not go out of my way or do it intentionally, I understand that trying to please everyone in life results in complete failure.  If you read my rants you already understand many of my opinions.  I will miss various interactions on that platform but what I will not miss are the rampant ignorant conversations, especially the blow ups during elections.  I will not miss the lost time spent trying to argue with unintellectual  brainless drones about how distorted their backwards view of the world may be.  Were there other options? Yes. I could have gone through and removed myself from groups, unshared photos, removed friends, etc. That would have taken more time and resulted in private messages asking why? How dare you? So I decided to go with who the fuck cares.  Burn it.  Time means more to me.  For some people the only way to kill something is to remove all associations to it.  So instead of just promising myself I would cut down interactions, stop posts, etc. I decided to make the cut.  This is no different than buying chocolate chip cookies and saying you are only going to eat one a week.  Yeah that lasts.  The other rebuttal will be, what about self control.  True.  That is a great point, but see my earlier point.  Fuck the noise.  When you truly focus on what you want in life, very few other things really truly matter.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So ask yourself, what matters to you?  Could that time you spend fat and laying on the couch spoon feeding nonsense into your brain be better spent elsewhere?  Why do you think Facebook or products like it are any fucking different from soap operas? It’s the same fucking crack.  Before you jump all over me, know this, I believe in social networks and platforms.  They have a solid purpose, but I favor micro networks over macro.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A well tailored service can be both very entertaining and beneficial to a customer and the content provider.  I believe they are worth paying and charging for.  While favor may rise and fall for a given platform the huge macro networks will never go away.  The larger they get, the more power they give to the smaller indie based networks who can truly tailor their products and services to a set of customers.  Customers who make a choice where to spend their priceless time.  Customers who think for themselves.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you want to connect with me, check my social logins.  I am not tied to any particular set of services and I reevaluate all the damn time.  I hope you do the same thing in life, because each second can never be reclaimed.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Open Letter To Car2Go</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/2014/03/04/open-letter-to-car2go/"/>
    <id>/2014/03/04/open-letter-to-car2go/</id>
    <published>2014-03-04T00:00:00-08:00</published>
    <updated>2014-03-04T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Hough</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;When my wife and I left Manhattan to head back West we moved to PDX completely blind. Neither of us had lived or visited there, but from our research everything seemed to fit.  To be absolutely honest, we watched too much Portlandia.&lt;!--more--&gt;During our first...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;When my wife and I left Manhattan to head back West we moved to PDX completely blind. Neither of us had lived or visited there, but from our research everything seemed to fit.  To be absolutely honest, we watched too much Portlandia.&lt;!--more--&gt;During our first summer fest we stumbled upon the brand &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://car2go.com"&gt;CAR2GO&lt;/a&gt;, a new car share service to the city.  Neither of us owned automobiles and we had planned on primarily using public transportation and purchasing bicycles.  I had used &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://zipcar.com/"&gt;Zipcar&lt;/a&gt; in Boulder, and I was a bit skeptical on their pricing and parking options, but &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://car2go.com"&gt;CAR2GO&lt;/a&gt; seemed very reasonable.  At the fest &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://car2go.com"&gt;CAR2GO&lt;/a&gt; brought two of their little go carts for people to review and they had a raffle wheel you could spin to get free starter minutes. As luck would have it, I ended up rolling the highest free minute slice of the wheel that day.  I signed up for my membership that same week, and we have been hooked ever since. So why I am writing this letter?  Just like any proud super fan would do, the answer is feedback.  I regularly reply to each of the surveys they send me, but I wanted to expand on something further.  A concept that I feel could help their system.  An idea that I would love to see developed.  A potential fix for what I call &lt;em&gt;dead zones in the play pen&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/images/posts/car2go-696256aa.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For those unfamiliar with &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://car2go.com"&gt;CAR2GO&lt;/a&gt; the play pen is what I call the geographical area inside of the operating home zone.  Basically, this it the zone that represents anywhere you can end a rental.  The go carts, or "&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://smartusa.com/"&gt;Smart Cars&lt;/a&gt;,” navigate around this pen at random with no referee to make sure the number of cars remains evenly dispersed throughout the pen, preventing tight clusters.  The result of no oversight is what I refer to as dead zones.  Dead zones can occur throughout the pen at various times of day, as a result of a major event such as big game or conference, or an area that does not see that much traffic overall.  In the current system and corresponding rental software in the car there does not appear to be a way to prevent this from happening.  In fact, it is often quite predictable depending on where  you live.  To prove my point, just review the &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://car2go.com"&gt;CAR2GO&lt;/a&gt; iPhone application each night for a week and you will see where clusters tend to form and where dead zones regularly occur.  While &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://car2go.com"&gt;CAR2GO&lt;/a&gt; prides themselves on a fixed pricing system, no parking fees, park nearly anywhere, etc.  this issue can be solved.  They do not need parking spots like &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://zipcar.com/"&gt;Zipcar&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://Getaround.com/"&gt;Getaround&lt;/a&gt;. They need an organic dynamic ai based referee.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So what is the referee?  In theory the referee would be software that continuouly monitors the grid to prevent clusters from occurring, or at least encourages users to prevent clusters themselves.  How does it achieve this goal?  Intelligent based discounting.  Take a look at the attached image.  Let’s say for a minute zone 1 is low on rentals.  Since the referee is monitoring the grid it can credit drivers who end rentals in the zone that  needs vehicles.  The overall pricing model does not change, but it gives a slight benefit to those willing to help out others.  Cost based incentives are proven to work.  There are users that regularly fill up cars will fuel just to get the minute credits.  Personally, I have never filled up a rental with gas yet.  While I would avoid the gas station, I would love to walk an extra few bucks to balance the grid.  Would the credits and zones be fixed? No.  The referee would adjust the zones to fit supply and demand and the credits should vary by time of day.  Peak times would have less of credit because the volume crossing paths in the grid should come close to balancing it, but at off peak the credits would be higher.  As an avid &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://car2go.com"&gt;CAR2GO&lt;/a&gt; user, and programmer, I believe this can be accomplished.  Expensive? Maybe, but a well balanced system driven by pure supply and demand should yield more rentals and more profits long term.  Also, customer satisfaction will improve because of availability.  I know it would make us happier, especially in the zone we live in.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you read this &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://twitter.com/car2go"&gt;@CAR2GO&lt;/a&gt;, let me know what you think... I will be attaching this thread to every survey you send me.  I think this spec can work.  Thank you for providing such an amazing service.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Diving Into The Deep End With Ruby</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/2014/02/10/diving-into-the-deep-end-with-ruby/"/>
    <id>/2014/02/10/diving-into-the-deep-end-with-ruby/</id>
    <published>2014-02-10T00:00:00-08:00</published>
    <updated>2014-02-10T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Hough</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Two years ago I started heading down the path of learning Ruby.  While I have been coding for a while now, I desperately wanted to get out of working in the ColdFusion language. Shocking right, ColdFusion is still a thing.  I would consider ColdFusion...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Two years ago I started heading down the path of learning Ruby.  While I have been coding for a while now, I desperately wanted to get out of working in the ColdFusion language. Shocking right, ColdFusion is still a thing.  I would consider ColdFusion and PHP about the same b.s. and anyone who argues that one is better than the other is basically debating the same sets of points on why ColdFusion  is better than PHP or vice versa.  They are merely using different colored markers to do so.  In my opinion ColdFusion will be the cobol of my generation. I knew that before I woke up one day obsolete, I had to make a change.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/images/posts/Learning-ca1880d7.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We all know there is a shortage of programmers right now, especially in the Ruby community.  Whether you are making the leap fresh, or you’re working to transition to modern technology, I hope these tips help you on that journey of discovery.  Let me start by saying, I am no expert in the language.  I believe in constant learning, and working with others to help build and realize their dreams.  My wife Kathryn Hough and I are building our startup in Ruby on Rails, and she is about to dive into the deep end with a formal code school &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.epicodus.com/"&gt;epicodus&lt;/a&gt; on February 17th.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why did I pick ruby?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After many conversations with members of the community, I came to agree with many of the core philosophies of the Ruby language.  In python there is often one prescribed way that people do things and everyone subscribes to that methodology. "Ruby inherited the Perl philosophy of having more than one way to do the same thing[&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://blog.simonwillison.net/post/58096277134/philosophyofruby"&gt;Quote&lt;/a&gt;]".  I correlated that reference with many of my friends running startups who were also using Ruby, and I loved the overall beauty of the language. Matsumoto, the founder of Ruby, has said that “Ruby is designed for programmer productivity and fun, following the principles of good user interface design. He stresses that systems design needs to emphasize human, rather than computer needs.[&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ruby_(programming_language)"&gt;Quote&lt;/a&gt;]”  Anyone who touches the language for the first time feels this in my opinion.  I was hooked from day one.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you have been playing around with the thought of learning to code, or learning a new language I would encourage you to give Ruby a try.  It is not a new language. It has been out for quite awhile and the Rails framework is very solid for building a variety of different applications.  If you are like me, coming over from ColdFusion, you will wonder in awe of waving bye bye to the lame tag syntax and lack of gems, bundler, etc.  Your life coding will be so much more enjoyable. So where do you begin? I was recently asked at my day gig to come up with a list of resources that I used to dive into the language.  I will warn you there are plenty of opinions baked into this list so read with caution.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hardware&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you’re running Windows, throw that machine out the window already and buy a Mac. If you are unable to or cannot afford a Mac, at least switch to a linux derivative. Use a VM if you have to.  Trust me, it will make your life so much easier.  Once you switch you will never look back.  If you need a sql server manager, don’t worry there are options.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Software&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ditch the IDEs for a text editor.  Download &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.sublimetext.com/3"&gt;Sublime Text&lt;/a&gt; 2, 3 if you are willing to pay for a license.  Get used to running terminal, &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.zsh.org/"&gt;zsh&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.iterm2.com"&gt;iterm2&lt;/a&gt;.  Ditch external tools for git as well. If you are looking for a solid setup, here are the &lt;a target="_blank" href="https://github.com/chrishough/myconfigurations"&gt;configurations&lt;/a&gt; I am currently running.   I regularly maintain that repo and feel free to ping me with questions. Purchase &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.alfredapp.com/"&gt;Alfredapp&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a target="_blank" href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/dash-docs-snippets/id458034879?mt=12"&gt;Dash&lt;/a&gt;.  Both of these applications are huge time savers and well worth the cost.  There are variety of setup guides and I am working on expanding my repo to support a single click install.  In time...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learning&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Depending on how greenfield you are to programming, I advise folks to take a few different paths.  If you are completely new, I would recommend a formal code school like &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.epicodus.com/"&gt;epicodus&lt;/a&gt; for a truly immersive experience.  Learning many of the principles of coding on your own can be very daunting.  Before my wife signed up for a formal class, she had already been through all of the &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://teamtreehouse.com/"&gt;Treehouse&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a target="_blank" href="https://www.codeschool.com/"&gt;Codeschool&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.codecademy.com/"&gt;Codecademy&lt;/a&gt; courses.  Depending on your skill set, I recommend all three.  If you are very novice, I would start with &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://teamtreehouse.com/"&gt;Treehouse&lt;/a&gt; first, than move on to &lt;a target="_blank" href="https://www.codeschool.com/"&gt;Codeschool&lt;/a&gt;. It will be frustrating.  It will take time.  Hold your head high and keep pushing forward.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you already know a language or two here are some pointers, to get your started.  I definitely recommend &lt;a target="_blank" href="https://www.codeschool.com/"&gt;Codeschool&lt;/a&gt; for learning the syntax,and picking up the following three books on &lt;a target="_blank" href="https://pragprog.com/"&gt;PragProg&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://pragprog.com/book/ruby4/programming-ruby-1-9-2-0"&gt;Programming Ruby&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://pragprog.com/book/achbd/the-rspec-book"&gt;Rspec&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://pragprog.com/book/rails4/agile-web-development-with-rails-4"&gt;Agile Development with Rails 4&lt;/a&gt;.  They are priceless.  I know you are already used to &lt;a target="_blank" href="https://stackoverflow.com/"&gt;stackoverflow&lt;/a&gt; but here are a good set of links I use all of the time:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://api.rubyonrails.org/"&gt;Ruby on Rails API&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.ruby-toolbox.com/"&gt;Ruby Toolbox&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://rubygems.org/"&gt;Ruby Gems&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/chrishough/myconfigurations/blob/master/ruby/conventions.md"&gt;Ruby Naming Conventions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://gist.github.com/rstacruz/1569572"&gt;Rails Model Cheatsheet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://pryrepl.org/"&gt;Pry: A powerful alternative to the standard IRB shell for Ruby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://railscasts.com/"&gt;Railscasts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Experiment.  Start off by building a few applications and following tutorials, you will be cracking away at it in no time.  Most importantly, be humble, listen to others for guidance.  It’s important to realize that not everything will transfer from your previous language so be patient.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Community&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I cannot emphasize this enough.  Join and participate in your local user group.  If you are in a rural town, start your own.  Trust me, you will find at least a few others to hack with on the weekend.  Reach out to others you connect with online to pair program remotely, and attend conferences.  Yes, conferences cost money, but you will learn and meet so many experts, you will more that double your money back in returns long term.  Here are a great set of podcasts that dive into many of the issues ruby programmers face day to day:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://rubyrogues.com/"&gt;Ruby Rogues&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.freelancersshow.com/"&gt;The Ruby Freelancers Show&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is not an exhaustive list, and I hope to write follow-ups in time.  Please let me know what you think.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>3 Years And Counting</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/2014/02/05/3-years-and-counting/"/>
    <id>/2014/02/05/3-years-and-counting/</id>
    <published>2014-02-05T00:00:00-08:00</published>
    <updated>2014-02-05T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Hough</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Cracking a jolly smile I walked into a pre-party for Ignite Boulder to meet up with close friends before the show.  One of my best friends introduced me to her friend named Kate. I was immediately struck with awe, but I had to muster up a solid conversation...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Cracking a jolly smile I walked into a pre-party for Ignite Boulder to meet up with close friends before the show.  One of my best friends introduced me to her friend named Kate. I was immediately struck with awe, but I had to muster up a solid conversation.  This was difficult at the time because I had already went to a pre-party before the pre-party! If you know Boulder, this is pretty easy to do.  Considering she was very new to town we started talking all things Boulder and soon we landed on the topic of cruiser bikes.  One of my friends at the time told me that any woman who would jump on the pegs on the back of a cruiser is a keeper.  I am usually not one for lines, but I had to drop it.  It sounded perfect for the situation.  I thought to myself, now is my chance, so I mentioned I wanted to get a california crusier and how cool it would be if she road on the back.  She laughed and was like “that would be sooo awesome!” To say the least I was immediately hooked.  We enjoyed a few more beers and exchanged twitter handles and went on our separate paths and nightly parties.  I did not want it to be over...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/images/posts/HoughsNYC-f4ad31f0.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That week I kept a close eye on twitter.  I knew she lived in Denver and that was honestly just too far away for a relationship to work.  Lucky for me she did come up to B-town regularly.  That following week, I woke up, and immediately grabbed my iphone to check the interwebs.  To my surprise, the lovely woman I was enamored with was hanging out at The Cup coffee shop.  It was just down the street from my crib on Pearl street.  I was like “oh damn, get your ass up, now is your chance!”  I immediately jumped out of bed, got dressed and road my bike down to get coffee.  As I approached the open garage door I noticed this fine pretty lady sitting just inside to the right.  My palms were sweaty and to say I was nervous, that would be an understatement.  I was freaking out.  So I walked around to the side door carefully, like a cat, so she wouldn’t see me and made my way to the bathroom in the back.  As I starred in the mirror I knew I had but one chance to start and hopefully finish this interaction.  Failure was not an option.  I literally cupped up a pool  of water splashed it on my face and looked deeply into the mirror.  While I will keep most of what I said to me, I will sum it up by saying “Chris you are a bad ass, you can do this! It’s go time.” I felt like a middle line backer on the home team running onto the field at the homecoming game.  I walked out of the bathroom, purchased a coffee and gracefully approached the lady I spent so much time laughing with at Ignite.  I looked at her and said: “Hey! Funny seeing you here?”  We started talking.  That single conversation lasted nearly 4 hours.  I didn’t want it to end....&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It didn’t....&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;3 years later, I am happier than I have ever been.  I feel like I have met the most powerful passionate success driven woman on the planet.  She inspires me, she pushes me to succeed, and she makes my heart smile no matter how hard I am on myself.  She taught how life could be an adventurous roller coaster ride if you're wiling to take your hands off the grips and hold them as high as possible.  I will be forever grateful for meeting my wife, my partner in crime, until my final breath.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Kathryn, I love you. I will always be by your side, and will work my hardest to work with you to build that rocket ship to the moon.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Hough Chocolate Martini</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/2013/12/15/hough-chocolate-martini/"/>
    <id>/2013/12/15/hough-chocolate-martini/</id>
    <published>2013-12-15T00:00:00-08:00</published>
    <updated>2013-12-15T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Hough</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I love cocktails and this is a pure classic. Try it!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/images/posts/ChocolateMartini-6cbaea1a.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;Stoli Vanilla: 1.5-2&lt;br&gt;Godiva Dark Chocolate: 1-1.5&lt;br&gt;Godiva White Chocolate: 1-1.5&lt;br&gt;Vanilla Extract&lt;br&gt;Hershey's Chocolate Syrup&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prep the Large Martini Shaker with Ice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;add 2-2.5 shots full of Stoli Vanilla&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;add...&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I love cocktails and this is a pure classic. Try it!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/images/posts/ChocolateMartini-6cbaea1a.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Stoli Vanilla: 1.5-2&lt;br /&gt;Godiva Dark Chocolate: 1-1.5&lt;br /&gt;Godiva White Chocolate: 1-1.5&lt;br /&gt;Vanilla Extract&lt;br /&gt;Hershey's Chocolate Syrup&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Prep the Large Martini Shaker with Ice&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;add 2-2.5 shots full of Stoli Vanilla&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;add 1-1.5 shots full of Godiva Dark Chocolate Liquor&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;add 1-1.5 shots full of Godiva White Chocolate Liquor&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;add splash (teaspoon) of Vanilla Extract&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Layer the top of the martini glass with Hershey's Chocolate syrup. Weave Pattern&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Shake 30sec - 1minute to blend all of the contents&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Pour into the martini glass using a mesh strainer to catch all of the ice&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;Enjoy!!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you like this recipe, check out this one: &lt;a href="/2012/12/01/hough-eggnog-martini/"&gt;Eggnog Martini&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Cascadia Ruby 2013</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/2013/10/25/cascadia-ruby-2013/"/>
    <id>/2013/10/25/cascadia-ruby-2013/</id>
    <published>2013-10-25T00:00:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-10-25T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Hough</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The more I dive into ruby the more I love the language and the community around it.&lt;!--more--&gt;This year I had the opportunity to attend both &lt;a href="/2013/05/04/rails-conference-2013/"&gt;Rails Conference&lt;/a&gt;[&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://lanyrd.com/2013/railsconf/"&gt;Lanyard&lt;/a&gt;] and &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://cascadiaruby.com/"&gt;Cascadia Ruby&lt;/a&gt;[&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://lanyrd.com/2013/cascadiaruby/"&gt;Lanyard&lt;/a&gt;] locally here in Portland, Oregon. Let me start by saying I loved...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The more I dive into ruby the more I love the language and the community around it.&lt;!--more--&gt;This year I had the opportunity to attend both &lt;a href="/2013/05/04/rails-conference-2013/"&gt;Rails Conference&lt;/a&gt;[&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://lanyrd.com/2013/railsconf/"&gt;Lanyard&lt;/a&gt;] and &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://cascadiaruby.com/"&gt;Cascadia Ruby&lt;/a&gt;[&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://lanyrd.com/2013/cascadiaruby/"&gt;Lanyard&lt;/a&gt;] locally here in Portland, Oregon. Let me start by saying I loved rails conference and I am much bigger fan of huge blow out events, but there is something very valuable
about smaller conferences like Cascadia. They kinda feel like a small rural town where everyone knows each other, instead of a
big city like Chicago where I grew up. This has both positive and negative consequences like cliques and extremely bad wifi,
but it also allows for a setting to have more time for one on one conversations. Over the course of a few days as a noob I
had the opportunity to meet quite a few great minds in the industry, make new friends, and learn quite a bit about topics
directly and indirectly related to code. While I enjoyed each of the topics presented, two of them stood out the most for me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/images/posts/cascadiaruby2013-5e8aca7d.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;My favorite code related topic was "&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://lanyrd.com/2013/cascadiaruby/scqmpf/"&gt;Advanced Multithreading in Ruby&lt;/a&gt;" by
 &lt;a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/jerrydantonio"&gt;Jerry D'Antonio&lt;/a&gt;. I am relatively new to ruby and rails, and I had never been exposed to that level of
 functionality in the language. Multithreading asynchronous processing can be a very powerful ally for applications under load,
 and it goes far beyond using delayed job for processing user sign up emails. In fact, at my day gig we were considering using a
 node.js installation for this type of functionality but I am no longer convinced that node would be the best setup for our
 needs. We can easily use &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://sidekiq.org/"&gt;Sidekiq&lt;/a&gt; or the suite of other gems to access other functional programming languages like
 clojure inside of the ruby paradigm. Unlike other conferences I have attended, not all of the sessions were just raw code.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/mandoescamilla"&gt;Mando Escamilla’s&lt;/a&gt; talk
 "&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://lanyrd.com/2013/cascadiaruby/scqmmz/"&gt;Tell Us Another Story, Grandpa: Lessons Learned Over 16 Years as a Developer&lt;/a&gt;" was by far, one of the best
 I talks have ever heard. As people with analytical minds, we developers look at the world very differently than many people we encounter. We have
 challenges in our personal lives that are a result of our dedication to our craft, our startup, building a business, and our focus. While
 everyone likes to focus on the the huge successes in our field, our lives are faced with choices and not every choice is as rosy as people
 like to communicate. We make sacrifices and sometimes face the harsh consequences of our life choices. Things are not easy, and I applaud
 the strength it too Mando to get up in front of us all and share his story. I learned quite a bit from this presentation, because we all
 have skeletons in the closet right. So what’s on deck?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now that 2013 is winding down for me, I am already planning for conferences next year. As of today here are goals for
 2014: Rails Conference, Ruby Conference, Lone Star Ruby Conference, and potentially others. I hope to see you there, just look for the guy in the fedora.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Co-Founder Drama</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/2013/09/28/co-founder-drama/"/>
    <id>/2013/09/28/co-founder-drama/</id>
    <published>2013-09-28T00:00:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-09-28T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Hough</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;If you are single founder or a team seeking help, I hope our experience helps you avoid the pitfalls we encountered when taking on a co-founder. While we always hear of the huge wins like the Twitter IPO, the ground is littered with failed ideas, relationships...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;If you are single founder or a team seeking help, I hope our experience helps you avoid the pitfalls we encountered when taking on a co-founder. While we always hear of the huge wins like the Twitter IPO, the ground is littered with failed ideas, relationships, and puddles of tears.  If you have followed my posts you already know I am brutally honest. Proceed with caution:  I am no expert. This is our first business, and we understand there is never a guarantee for success in entrepreneurship.  These life lessons learned this past summer, these “stupid taxes,” are the scars that help us remember to never make the same mistake twice.  Before I can express the lessons we learned, let me tell you the story.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/images/posts/spraypaint-e3832612.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;My wife and I have been building a business for over a year now.  We both work full time, and unfortunately we both have school debt. Like any idea, we pivoted a few times into different industries and we are primarily interested in growing lean without venture capital if at all possible.  You may refer to this as a side project, which everyone in technology nowadays has one. Our baby was no different, and this past summer we wanted to ramp up development in areas where our skills were lacking.  I have always been a huge fan of meetups, and regularly started attending the geek hotspots in our community.  As luck would have it, we encountered a great opportunity to bring on a co-founder who was already working with a product in similar market space.  We quickly all became friends and believed it was a match made in heaven.  Instead, it turned out to be a wasted three months and thousands of dollars in stock split and legal fees. So what did we learn?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[1] Work ethic&lt;/strong&gt; is the single most important factor in evaluating a co-founder and building a team.  If you’re all working full time jobs, agree to a number of hours you expect to work outside of the day job and stick to it.  Measure it.  Building a business takes blood, sweat, and tears.  It takes commitment both to the dream, and the work itself.  If you are the only one &lt;a href="/2013/01/01/who-is-online-at-2am/"&gt;online at 2am&lt;/a&gt; this will build resentment, distrust, and disloyalty in the organization.  Trust me on this, if you get the feeling they will not be there with you at the early hours of the morning, they will not be there when bugs arise under tight deadlines. &lt;a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/jason"&gt;@Jason&lt;/a&gt; states this better than I can: &lt;em&gt;“..Startup life, it’s not a game. Don’t work at a startup if you’re not into it–go work at the post office or stabucks if you’re not into it you want balance in your life.”&lt;/em&gt;(&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://calacanis.com/2008/03/07/how-to-save-money-running-a-startup-17-really-good-tips/"&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt; There is nothing wrong with the 9-5, it’s a great life, and not everyone is cutout for startups and building businesses.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tightly coupled to work ethic is &lt;strong&gt;[2] Self-Motivation&lt;/strong&gt;. It should be no surprise to you that many business executives are also health and fitness junkies.  They love adrenaline, and they do not need someone on their back to fuel their fire.  It comes from within.  They are capable of digging deep, fighting through the pain, and using their internal energy to break through any obstacle in their path.  I believe each person ofthe founding team needs to have this trait, and it must be part of their dna.  You cannot convince someone to be self motivated so do not waste yourtime, move on to the next better candidate.  The constant headache of dealing with whining and lack of interest will be cumbersome and slow you down.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you’ve made it through the work ethic, and past self-motivation, it’s time to talk &lt;strong&gt;[3] Legal and Finances&lt;/strong&gt;.  Considering I almost left technology for finance, and we were lucky enough to have a great attorney, we excelled in this area.  When we grew the team we rebalanced the shares so everyone was equal at 25% with 25% percent unallocated.  Our attorney advised against this because we had already been working on the business for over a year, but I believe in being fair.  It was still such an early stage, it made sense to be equal.  Where I did agree with legal was the cliff.  If you do not have a vesting schedule with a 1 year minimum cliff, you are doing it wrong.  In our case, the original team started at the cliff and the new co-founder had to wait 12 months.  This decision ended up saving our ass.  When the co-founder quit the business it was easy to buy back the shares.   Along those lines, we also had provisions baked in giving the corporation first right of refusal to buy back shares at a later date if neccessary. We also had our books in “ocd” like order and every transaction was documented and accounted for since the business was created.  This made the separation much easier, especially considering in our case the separation was voluntary.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If all of the reasons above have passed with flying colors, it’s time to talk about the &lt;strong&gt;[4] Technology Stack&lt;/strong&gt;.  Make sure the new co-founder is versed in the technology stack you are building the project in.  In our case, we had laid the foundation in rails, yet we made the mistake of bringing on a person who had no experience in ruby or rails. They only knew python.  While I have no problems with python, it’s a great language, in a small team it makes more sense to be very familiar with the same sets of technology, at least for the mvp. This caused us multiple headaches and rework because of the lack of knowledge of how ruby on rails worked.  At the same time, make sure you take the time to evaluate the candidate's skill set, especially if you are looking for someone to compliment your own.  If you need Sass and design cutup, inquire up front.  Do not make assumptions, and ask for a portfolio.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Finally commit to &lt;strong&gt;[5] Measurements&lt;/strong&gt; and keep everyone honest.  While we had regularly scheduled project planning meetings, and an agile sprint cycle, we failed to monitor check ins.  Any startup worth a penny makes code commits daily.  This should never be a debate, and not even optional.  If you have made it this far in your evaluation, this part should be assumed, if not laughable.  Stick to your deliverables and track everyone’s progress.  One of our strengths was documentation, we documented everything that was great, and everything that was a failure. While I am sure I can go on and on, these lists are highly variable in nature, and definitely not all inclusive.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I hope this has helped you, if at most, sparked a few ideas and concerns in your brain.  Let me reiterate, I am no expert, but I believe in &lt;a href="/2013/05/06/constant-learning/"&gt;constant learning&lt;/a&gt;.  I will leave one final thought since I love using analogies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Make sure that you surround yourself with A players only if you want to win. The best pirate ship has an A captain, A people firing the cannons, and A people cleaning the deck.  Not everyone is good at controlling the sails. Over the course of its life, not all shipmates will reach the final resting place.  The perfect combination of players and skills will yield the gold and spoils of battle.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Github Git Hooks</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/2013/09/23/github-git-hooks/"/>
    <id>/2013/09/23/github-git-hooks/</id>
    <published>2013-09-23T00:00:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-09-23T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Hough</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Recently I spent a small chunk of time exploring what I could do with git hooks.  My goal was to append a message on every commit with the correct git hub url to it's corresponding commit url at git hub.  This was no easy feat from what I discovered...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Recently I spent a small chunk of time exploring what I could do with git hooks.  My goal was to append a message on every commit with the correct git hub url to it's corresponding commit url at git hub.  This was no easy feat from what I discovered and I definitely lost a few hairs over it. In the end, I took on the battle and won.&lt;!--more--&gt;If you have been following my &lt;a target="_blank" href="https://github.com/chrishough/myconfiguration"&gt;Coder Setups&lt;/a&gt; these are three files that are included in my bundle.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;First the git cloning utility properly setups the cloned repo and installs each hook.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code id="gist-8092445"data-file="clone.sh"&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This commit-msg hook automatically adds the branch name and branch description to every commit message.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code id="gist-8092445"data-file="commit_msg_add_branch_name.sh"&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This post-commit hook automatically adds a note to each commit with the correct github url.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code id="gist-8092445"data-file="post_commit_add_github_commit_note.sh"&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Intrinsic Motivation</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/2013/09/12/intrinsic-motivation/"/>
    <id>/2013/09/12/intrinsic-motivation/</id>
    <published>2013-09-12T00:00:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-09-12T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Hough</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;If you think that technology is a 9 to 5 gig, please stop reading this article right now.  Go back to your couch, crack open a bud, turn on your favorite show, and zone back out.  In fact, take it one step further.  Call a friend over to take a photo...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;If you think that technology is a 9 to 5 gig, please stop reading this article right now.  Go back to your couch, crack open a bud, turn on your favorite show, and zone back out.  In fact, take it one step further.  Call a friend over to take a photo of you sitting there aimlessly watching TV.  Mount the photo on your wall because you will be in that same place, withering away, until your time on this wonderful planet expires. Technology, startups, and building businesses are a 24 hours a day job.  It is part of life, and it should be part of your DNA.  To think otherwise is not only naive, it’s quite short cited.  The world is evolving every second regardless of your participation.  I have been on call every day since I started coding, and not a day goes by when I do not feel behind.  Here’s the definition for those that need it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Intrinsic motivation refers to motivation that is driven by an interest or enjoyment in the task itself, and exists within the individual rather than relying on external pressures or a desire for reward.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;footer&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;cite&gt;&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Motivation"&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/footer&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Over the years, I have always wondered what it takes to be successful.  One of my favorite quotes from a &lt;a href="/2013/01/01/who-is-online-at-2am/"&gt;video I wrote about&lt;/a&gt;is:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;I am here to tell you that most of you want to be successful, but you don’t want it bad, you just kinda want it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;footer&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Eric Thomas&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;cite&gt;&lt;a href="http://youtu.be/lsSC2vx7zFQ"&gt;Eric Thomas&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/footer&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I live by this every day, and I have come to accept that not everyone wants it.  People look for reasons, for excuses, or worse yet point blame at the so called 1% for why they are NOT this or that.  The answer is in the mirror, yet many do not want to realize it.  Another favorite rant of mine is from Adam Corolla, when he went off about the occupy wall street movement.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;There goes Mr. Jenkins. Look up to him. That guy works hard. That guy built a company. That guy built an empire. Now look at him. He’s got his Rolls Royce. He’s drivin’ up the hill.  But what do we do now? Now it’s like: Oh, look at him. Look at him. Does he need that car? Why’s he need that car? I’m drivin’ a fuckin’ Chevette! Why’s he get to drive that fuckin’ car, you know? Let’s go up there and throw a rock at it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;footer&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Adam Corolla&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/footer&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Every day I leave the gym, working to slim down my fat ass and I walk by at least a half dozen one hundred thousand dollar cars.  I’m do not feel jealousy, I feel inspired, I set my goals higher, and push on.  I watched my family work day in and day out.  When I was younger I did not understand why they were gone all the time but as I grew up, and matured the answer was clear.  They realized that in order for me to break free of the chains that restricted their lives they had to make sacrifices.  While I was not the poorest kid in my school growing up, I can say I was certainly towards the bottom.  While I never acted like it, I pretended I lived in a reality far different from what I came home to each day.  Being exposed to options, executives running major businesses, and a hard lined grading scale meant I had little time for error. It instilled a drive in me to succeed that has kept me alive throughout all of the lows in my life.   This passion, my dreams have never faded and while not all of them have come to fruition, many of them have.  It’s how I live. It’s my DNA.  Not too long ago I was asked by a friend if I do everything in my life with 110% effort.  I looked at hime and replied:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yes, anything worth doing, worth taking the time out of the precious moments we have, is worth doing 110%.  If it’s not, why waste time doing it at all?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;footer&gt;&lt;strong&gt;@chrishough&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/footer&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I was happy to be a part of the generation where many kids did not get trophies for shit they never did, or even lifted a finger to help.  I rode the pine during sports, and I understand what that feels like.  While I am not expert at the game of life, I do understand that I have to play.  When the game is over, I will be dead.  The bigger question I ask myself is whether or not I have accomplished everything I wanted to do.  You see, I believe I am not crazy. I believe that there are others out there who are intrinsically motivated to succeed.  They do not need a carrot on a stick in front of them and they do not care what people think.  They run over the obstacles regardless if they are economic, human, family, friends, or personal holdups.  In life you will rarely encounter these people, and they are often confused or portrayed as workaholics.  Trust me, they are not.  These are the folks that are going to build businesses.  These are the folks that could care less about who won the big game, and are more interested in how their company is going to succeed. I hope I am one of those lucky few.  My life has had many highs and lows, but I live by these dreams and values.  The other day I was taking to my wife about life, business, and relationships and I compared my life to a short bus.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;People are either on my short bus or off of it.  It’s a crazy ride that not everyone wants to ride on, no one rides for free, and not everyone at the final stop was there at the beginning.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;footer&gt;&lt;strong&gt;@chrishough&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/footer&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I understand that not everyone I encounter will be compatible with me, and I am ok with that.  I love my friends, and would take a bullet for my loved ones.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;P.S.  I will leave you with one final example.  If you are a programmer working in relaxed fortune 500 corporate 9-5 job in a computer language that isconsidered obsolete, and you are not working 24hrs a day to up your chops, do not be surprised by the meteor that lands on you.  The dinosaurs did not see it coming either.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Tired Of Pizza And Beer</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/2013/06/20/tired-of-pizza-and-beer/"/>
    <id>/2013/06/20/tired-of-pizza-and-beer/</id>
    <published>2013-06-20T00:00:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-06-20T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Hough</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Dear conference and meetup organizers, small businesses, startup teams, and whomever else wishes to listen.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/images/posts/pizza-fcb8b49a.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Can we move past the stereotypical pizza and beer events?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you have ever wanted to lose weight, and found  yourself rushing to an evening meetup...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Dear conference and meetup organizers, small businesses, startup teams, and whomever else wishes to listen.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/images/posts/pizza-fcb8b49a.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Can we move past the stereotypical pizza and beer events?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you have ever wanted to lose weight, and found  yourself rushing to an evening meetup after work without time to grab dinner, you know what I'm talking about.  Event organizers,  this crappy food you are serving at your events is contributing to rising healthcare costs in our nation and making everyone sick and tired. Please rethink this strategy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you are worried about alienating the developers and designers who are expecting pizza and beer thanks to years of social conditioning, that's ok.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At a minimum, please offer a snack table or meal option for those of us who want to keep it healthy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have attended events like these in every city I have lived in. To be honest, I am calling officer shenanigans on this bullshit.  By handing out pizza and cheap beer, you might as well be handing out free supersized fries and McDonalds cheeseburgers.  I mean, what's the difference?  Maybe a few of us geeks are concerned about the way we look, the way we fit into our clothes, the way we smell, the list goes on and on.  I know there are others out there with me that are sick of this broad stroke approach.  It feels amateurish and it's meant to appease the geek crowd.  Let’s face it, it’s just plain easy and cheap to just phone in twenty pizza hut gmo infested pizzas instead of going to the local grocery store or farmers market to pick up ingredients for a salad.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yes there was a time in my life when this worked for me, but I am over it.  I am over the cheap beer and appetizers and honestly I would rather see geek events with healthy food, or at a damn minimum a healthy set of options free of GMOs, and free of high fructose corn syrup.  Is setting up a blender for fruit or veggie smoothies really hard?  While I am not in charge of an office, and no I do not run a meetup or conference I want to share these emotions with those that may.  Please consider this going forward.  How about we start talking about geek races, team events to the local rock climbing gym, or hell free gym passes.  Are there firms out there that already practice this? Of course, but many if not most, still just pass out pizza and beer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Over my career I use to see the middle aisles of various corporations piled high with donuts, bottles of soda, and every assortment of treats you can think of.  I would watch people consume this garbage than sit down all day, and towards the end of the day get exhausted, tired, sugar rushes running down.  Most would complain of their weight, their looks, some depressed, than reach for another donut and head straight back to the cube.  I was one of those folks.  So if you have read this far, and you actually hear my plea, please consider a change.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Please consider the folks that may be working hard to avoid the high fructose corn syrup infested soda, the gmo high carb pizza, and sugar packed ice cream.  These people are your friends, family, and co-workers.  They are working hard to have the bodies they want, not the prescribed American fatty diet the food corporations think we should have.  Trust me, it’s not that we do not want to eat that food, we do.  I have the same cravings you do, but I actually care what the numbers are on the scale.  Too long I have watched those numbers increase. Too long I have seen this occur.  I hope there are others out there that support this. I hope maybe at least one person thinks twice next time.  I live with this dream as I will continue to battle with food until the day I die.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I know I do not walk alone.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Hacking A Standing Desk</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/2013/05/28/hacking-a-standing-desk/"/>
    <id>/2013/05/28/hacking-a-standing-desk/</id>
    <published>2013-05-28T00:00:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-05-28T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Hough</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I know there are many variations for standing desk solutions online, but after tons of research, none of them met my needs.&lt;!--more--&gt;Yes, I like &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.geekdesk.com/"&gt;Geek Desks&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.anthro.com/"&gt;Anthro Carts&lt;/a&gt; but they are way expensive and are pretty ugly.  I loved my old school tanker desk, especially...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I know there are many variations for standing desk solutions online, but after tons of research, none of them met my needs.&lt;!--more--&gt;Yes, I like &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.geekdesk.com/"&gt;Geek Desks&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.anthro.com/"&gt;Anthro Carts&lt;/a&gt; but they are way expensive and are pretty ugly.  I loved my old school tanker desk, especially for drawing so I needed something to adapt to it. While I am not a huge fan of &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.ikea.com/us/en/"&gt;IKEA&lt;/a&gt; they offered a great price to benefit ratio on my proposed configuration.  This cost me $25, not counting labor.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Components required:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;$9.99 - &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.ikea.com/us/en/catalog/products/40104270/#/80104268"&gt;LACK&lt;/a&gt; Side table, black-brown&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;$14.99 - &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.ikea.com/us/en/catalog/products/20049538/"&gt;CAPITA&lt;/a&gt; Leg, stainless steel&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Standard sized phillips screwdriver&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/images/posts/standingdesk2-4956e537.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This configuration replaces the legs that come with the standard Lack side table reducing the overall height to just over 10 inches, plus there are really only a few steps to complete this.  Merely turn over the lack table and install the 4 Capita legs.  Use a ruler if you wish to be precise, and it also helps to pre-drill the holes.  Do not use a power drill to screw in the legs. TRUST ME, you WILL STRIP the cheap wood the furniture is made out of forcing you to reposition the legs, or worse replace the entire table.  Down the road I am planning on acquiring an &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.amazon.com/dp/B003BYRDKM/?tag=noconf-20"&gt;anti-fatigue mat&lt;/a&gt; to prevent knee strain and help reduce back pain.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here's my setup:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/images/posts/standingdesk.JPG" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Recycled Design</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/2013/05/23/recycled-design/"/>
    <id>/2013/05/23/recycled-design/</id>
    <published>2013-05-23T00:00:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-05-23T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Hough</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;How do we deal with permanence in our code and design?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I know we have all come across that developer or designer who is so tightly coupled to their previous work that you almost have to pry their dead cold fingers off of their previous accomplishments...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;How do we deal with permanence in our code and design?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I know we have all come across that developer or designer who is so tightly coupled to their previous work that you almost have to pry their dead cold fingers off of their previous accomplishments before they let go.  Sadly, I have been guilty of this same phenomena many times growing up.  It’s hard to let go, especially when you have put so much blood, sweat, and tears into a project. As I have gotten older I have come to learn and appreciate that everything we work on evolves, just like we humans.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/images/posts/Coins-c8cef949.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We have to get better. We have to learn.  This means that our code and our designs will inevitably change.  Now there are two waysto look at this. We can either be very stubborn and resist it, or we can dive in head first and embrace it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the core principles I have learned in the ruby community is code is disposable.  There are an infinite number of ways to approach a problem, so iterate quickly, build what your customers want, and do not be afraid to rebuild and rearchitect sections of legacy code as needed. In fact, it’s your job.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Huedio coins were our first business cards, and I spent a chunk of time working on them for our initial startup idea. No, I am not an expert designer, but I would like to think I am creative.  The fist was meant to symbolize “fuck the system” and everything that controls it.  The project was targeting hyper local indie makers seeking to become breakout successes.  The makers bunk the trends set by the mainstream Walmarts and IKEAs pushing forward their own dreams and visions.  While we ultimately pivoted away from this idea, I viewed the evolution of the logo my first successful experience dealing with design permanence.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/images/posts/logotransition-bbfc3362.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The logo went through multiple renditions and even the business cards had several layouts to accomplish the exact look and feel of the laser cuts on cedar we desired.  Even though we moved far away from this concept, I was determined to use the logo I loved.  I decided to recycle it.  Instead of getting pissed and just throwing it away, I used it for my blog.  I think it turned out pretty good and when I have more free time I know I will dabble at tooling it even more.  Not conforming is one of my core values, in fact NoConformity, in kanji, is tattooed under the &lt;a href="/pages/artwork/"&gt;corporate robot committing suicide on my left wrist&lt;/a&gt;.  The moral of the story is, we need to get  used to impermanence, embrace it, and evolve as fast as we can.  In our code, in life, change and evolution are what keep the world moving forward.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I say subscribe to the future, because living in the past = death.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A few great examples of recycled design.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/images/posts/Logos_Evolve-Infographic-b1764098.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/18/logos-change-over-time_n_3110194.html?utm_hp_ref=tw#slide=more291871"&gt;Image Source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The wooden nickels were laser cut from cedar and required multiple sample editions to get the correct depth and readability.  If you arelooking for wooden cards contact &lt;a mailto="frank@customwoodencards.com"&gt;Frank Urbano&lt;/a&gt; at &lt;a href="http://customwoodencards.com"&gt;customwoodencards.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Constant Learning</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/2013/05/06/constant-learning/"/>
    <id>/2013/05/06/constant-learning/</id>
    <published>2013-05-06T00:00:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-05-06T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Hough</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;What it is about getting older that severely limits or destroys completely our innate human ability to adapt to our surroundings?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/images/posts/SteveJobs-63ab382e.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Children fight through the scars of learning to ride a bike or getting pegged in the face with a baseball on their first...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;What it is about getting older that severely limits or destroys completely our innate human ability to adapt to our surroundings?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/images/posts/SteveJobs-63ab382e.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Children fight through the scars of learning to ride a bike or getting pegged in the face with a baseball on their first game.  They get up and
   fight another day.  Their fearless attitudes and dedication to learning something new helps shape the world around them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Adults on the other hand seem to follow a very different path.  Many people I have encountered in my life are better at cracking open a can of shitty beer and complaining at the senseless chatter on television than learning a new skill.  Regardless of what these people believe, their worlds are changing rapidly.  Many of us encounter a good number of these folks everyday.  No matter how hard we work to try to change them, nothing works.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have always stated that being a leader is a lonely road, and that road comes with many different types of obstacles that one must navigate around. I believe there is a direct correlation between those that are successful and those that continue to get scars from riding new bikes or getting hit by baseballs.  They believe getting up to bat, taking the hits, and learning the game is part of life.  They believe they will hit a home run one day. While nothing is guaranteed, they believe that having tried and failed is far better than have never tried at all.  This is how I approach learning.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Many of my old friends stuck in their careers or old computer languages have inquired how to stay relevant in a changing society. Just like there is no training class for riding a bike, there is no prescribed path on learning to code.  You have to be willing to fight and learn something new each day.It will be frustrating.  It will be a complete pain in the ass.  That is life.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;My wife has been learning to code over the past month. She spends an hour a day grokking &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://teamtreehouse.com"&gt;treehouse&lt;/a&gt; and yes she gets frustrated, but each and every day she learns something new.  This makes me proud.  So if you are at the beginning check out my post on how &lt;a href="/2012/04/25/every-kid-gets-a-trophy/"&gt;every kid gets a trophy&lt;/a&gt;. If you are just looking to dive into ruby and rails here are some great resourcesI have used outside of my &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://codeschool.zferral.com/l/98/71262"&gt;codeschool&lt;/a&gt; membership.  I know this list is not complete and in fact changes everyday.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://rubyrogues.com/"&gt;Ruby Rogues Podcast&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://pragprog.com/book/rails4/agile-web-development-with-rails"&gt;Agile Web Development with Rails&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://pragprog.com/book/ruby4/programming-ruby-1-9-2-0"&gt;Programming Ruby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://tryruby.org/levels/1/challenges/0"&gt;Try Ruby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://guides.rubyonrails.org/getting_started.html"&gt;Rails Guides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://railscasts.com/pro"&gt;Railscasts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://iwanttolearnruby.com/"&gt;I Want to Learn Ruby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.rubytapas.com/episodes"&gt;Ruby Tapas&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="https://github.com/chrishough/myconfigurations"&gt;My Current Workstation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Let me know what your favorites are.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you can focus on the end zone you will get there over time.  Stop pretending you can just throw a hail mary or use “Emmit Smith HB Sweep Left” for those of us familiar with the skewed stats of John Madden Football 95.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Grok. Trunk. Live.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Rails Conference 2013</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/2013/05/04/rails-conference-2013/"/>
    <id>/2013/05/04/rails-conference-2013/</id>
    <published>2013-05-04T00:00:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-05-04T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Hough</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have heard many people say that you can get the same value out of a conference by watching it on tv or a screencast after the big show. To be honest with you, I think that’s completely b.s. Would the same people say they get the same value out of...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have heard many people say that you can get the same value out of a conference by watching it on tv or a screencast after the big show. To be honest with you, I think that’s completely b.s. Would the same people say they get the same value out of watching the pyramids on The Discovery Channel versus seeing them in person? I highly doubt it. I have attended numerous conferences in my past and can say without a doubt that coughing up the money for the entrance fees is well worth it. If your company does not pay for it, save for it like I did.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/images/posts/dhhkeynote-0017623c.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This was my first Rails Conference and it was the best conference I have attended by far. The sheer number of geeks at the sold out show was impressive, and overall it was the most diverse out of any I have previously attended. I attended numerous talks in my &lt;a href="/2013/04/28/my-first-rails-conference/"&gt;conference schedule&lt;/a&gt; and only a few were lackluster. I met a lot of people that are now in my digital rolodex both inside and outside the speaking sessions and the many evening events. It made for a killer week. I also was able to sit front row for the &lt;a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/dhh"&gt;dhh&lt;/a&gt; keynote. Before I get into my topic takeaways I must highlight a few things.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you are considering &lt;a href="/2013/05/06/constant-learning/"&gt;learning to code&lt;/a&gt;, now is the time. There are so many startups looking for you to join great teams. The number of businesses expanding in rails is astronomical, and the conference job board was literally packed with numbers and emails to call. Second, I only counted 10, literally 10 PCs out of the sold out 1500+ attendees. While this was reported on our #irc channel, I in fact only saw one, and that one, sadly, was running windows. I must admit I shed a tear for that poor soul. I have battled the Windows die hard crowd so many times over the course of my career being the only Apple user in a sea of PCs at my day gigs. Here though, I felt at home.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Enough of the MSFT trolling, here are few of my topic takeaways.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I learned quite about about APIs and tackling scalability. As I continue to work on my startup in the evenings, scalability and the issues surrounding it have been a concern. I no longer worry about it. One of the consistent messages baked into the rails and ruby communities is code is disposable. We do not have to stick to it like glue! So build fast, build what your customers want, track where your bottlenecks are, and appropriately fix those bottlenecks when required. You do no need to setup an expensive &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.pcmag.com/encyclopedia/term/44213/heterogeneous-environment"&gt;heterogeneous&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://blog.maxindelicato.com/2009/01/heterogeneous-vs-homogeneous-system-architectures.html"&gt;system architecture&lt;/a&gt; day one if you have not tested what your customers will want. A &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.pcmag.com/encyclopedia/term/44332/homogeneous-environment"&gt;homogeneous&lt;/a&gt; system may work just fine. Make sure you are not wasting your money, time, and resources. &lt;a target="_blank" href="https://gist.github.com/naoyamakino/5505375"&gt;Learning from Jony Ive, Orwell, and the Kano&lt;/a&gt; was an amazing talk, and if you are not familiar with the 5 basic principles of an API check out that talk, but most importantly, watch &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.objectifiedfilm.com/"&gt;Objectified&lt;/a&gt;. Compared to working in other languages I enjoyed the talks on naming conventions, proper structure, and overall code simplicity. I agree that code should be self documenting, easy to read, easy to adapt, however, it does not need to last forever. Even the best systems or code blocks are replaced. That is the nature of software evolution. My favorite session was “&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.justin.tv/confreaks/c/2250625"&gt;How to Talk to Developers by Ben Orenstein&lt;/a&gt;." Watch it. It was hilarious.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While I only highlighted a few of my takeaways, I learned something in every session I attended. I have been learning ruby and rails for sometime now and I continue to look forward to learning more and more in the ruby community. I hope to see you at &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://rubyconf.org/"&gt;Ruby Conference&lt;/a&gt; in Miami.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>My First Rails Conference</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/2013/04/28/my-first-rails-conference/"/>
    <id>/2013/04/28/my-first-rails-conference/</id>
    <published>2013-04-28T00:00:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-04-28T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Hough</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;When I left college, I never planned on being where I am  today.  I learned over time never to question these things, you only waste time. I have been programming in an old language called ColdFusion for very long time.  Yes, I get made fun of every...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;When I left college, I never planned on being where I am  today.  I learned over time never to question these things, you only waste time. I have been programming in an old language called ColdFusion for very long time.  Yes, I get made fun of every time I mention this to my fellow geeks, but what can I say, I love what I do. I would call myself software language agnositic, however, on hardware I’m all Apple fanboy.  CF is a great language, it served its purpose just like many others and I do not regret working in it during each day.  At night, however, I grok out to Ruby and Rails in the darkness.  It makes me happy.  It excites me.  I have attended many of the great CF conferences over the years including CFObjective and CFUnited and had a blast at each one.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/images/posts/FirstRailsConf-a0ef4faf.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have been learning Ruby over the last year. I am bulding a startup in it.  While I have learned so much in ColdFusion, especially from the community, I look forward to diving into my first Rails Conference and meeting many of the leaders of Ruby on Rails community.  Once I got my first taste of the Ruby language I was hooked. I hope to meet many of you tomorrow. So if you see a geek with a fedora [hopefully there is not many of us] say hello.  I am eager to meet you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So let’s kick ass, take names, and have a blast this week. Here is my schedule of events.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mon 4/29&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Morning announcements and opening keynote - David Heinemeier Hansson&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;How Shopify Scales Rails - John Duff&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Nobody will Train You but You - Zach Briggs&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Simple and Elegant Rails Code with Functional Style - Attila Domokos&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Object-Oriented Lessons for a Service-Oriented World - Chris Kelly&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Rails is Just Ruby - Jesse Wolgamott&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Humanity On Rails - Daniel Azuma&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Evening announcements and keynote - Michael Lopp&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Rails Conference Mixer at Spirit of 77 - Pivotal Labs&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tue 4/30&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Morning announcements and keynote - Yehuda Katz&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Make Your Application Snappier With Asynchronous Workers - Dave Kapp&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Cache = Cash! - Stefan Wintermeyer&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Introducing Brainstem, your companion for rich Rails APIs - Andrew Cantino&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Designing great APIs: Learning from Jony Ive, Orwell, and the Kano Model - Jon Dahl&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Data Storage: NoSQL Toasters and a Cloud of Kitchen Sinks - Casey Rosenthal&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Pry — The Good Parts! - Conrad Irwin&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;A Night in the Ruby Sky - New Relic&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wed 5/1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Morning announcements and keynote - James Duncan Davidson&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Describing Your World with Seahorse - Trevor Rowe&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Services and Rails: The Sh*t They Don't Tell You - Brian Morton&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Zero-downtime payment platforms - Prem Sichanugrist and Ryan Twomey&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Configuration Management Patterns - Beau Harrington&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Lightning talks&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Evening announcements and the Ruby Hero Awards&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Heroku/JumpStart Lab Performance Workshop&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Code School Night at Ground Kontrol&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Super Sweet RailsConf After Party at Elemental Technologies&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thu 5/2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;How to Talk to Developers - Ben Orenstein&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Dissecting Ruby with Ruby - Richard Schneeman&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Closing announcements and keynote - Aaron Patterson&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>My 2013 Goals</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/2013/01/21/my-2013-goals/"/>
    <id>/2013/01/21/my-2013-goals/</id>
    <published>2013-01-21T00:00:00-08:00</published>
    <updated>2013-01-21T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Hough</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I know everyone puts a spin on their own goals for the year, but while I have set goals, this is my first attempt at publicly locking them in.  Since leaving Chicago, I have endured a huge amount of transformation, not all by choice.  At the end of...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I know everyone puts a spin on their own goals for the year, but while I have set goals, this is my first attempt at publicly locking them in.  Since leaving Chicago, I have endured a huge amount of transformation, not all by choice.  At the end of the day, I believe I am where I am supposed to be right now more so than ever before.  I have grown to love the roller coaster of life and I have not looked back.  Every footstep out and away from my home town has been both an adventure and very rewarding. As a geek and huge fan boy, I must admit this quote means a lot to me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Your time is limited, so don't waste it living someone else's life. Don't be trapped by dogma — which is living with the results of other people's thinking. Don't let the noise of others' opinions drown out your own inner voice. And most important, have the courage to follow your heart and intuition. They somehow already know what you truly want to become. Everything else is secondary.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;footer&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Steve Jobs, Apple Computers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/footer&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So as I begin to embark on the journey of 2013, I have the following on my mind. #Planned&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Drop 30 pounds.  I am sick of looking like a fat ass, and this extra weight is slowing me down.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Run in at least two races this summer.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Maintain on average 3-4 days of CrossFit each week.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Become PROFICIENT at Ruby, the Rails Framework, and Postgres.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Launch my startup's first product line.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Pay off our family credit card and fix a few more debt related issues from the back in the day.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Hit the publish key at least once a week.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Learn to breathe and get back into yoga regularly for my spirituality.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Publish at least one open source project.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Finish my Coldbox conversion and complete overhaul project at my day gig.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Practice listening first, no matter how frustrating the other person may be.  We can not force others to awaken.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;I believe in constant learning, and as long as I pick up something new each and every day I believe I will end up where my dream wants to take me.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Hacking A Sunriser</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/2013/01/19/hacking-a-sunriser/"/>
    <id>/2013/01/19/hacking-a-sunriser/</id>
    <published>2013-01-19T00:00:00-08:00</published>
    <updated>2013-01-19T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Hough</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;When we moved to Portland, Oregon in August 2012 we had been warned about the dark winters.  Needless to say it was a rude awakening and much harder for me to deal with than I had anticipated.  If you ever consider moving to the Pacific Northwest I...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;When we moved to Portland, Oregon in August 2012 we had been warned about the dark winters.  Needless to say it was a rude awakening and much harder for me to deal with than I had anticipated.  If you ever consider moving to the Pacific Northwest I will tell you the rain will be tolerable but the lack of sun may be the deal breaker for you and your family. If you think about it, when it's raining working long hours becomes a lot easier to handle especially if everyone is inside.&lt;!--more--&gt;When we lived in Boulder, Colorado it was far more difficult to grind out code while your friends are right outside your window playing frisbee.  After just dealing with it through December, I noticed it was getting harder and harder for me to get out of bed each day.  Yes, we were already taking vitamin D supplements but I needed something more.  My body was missing the sun.  I started researching solutions to this issue when a fellow coder at the &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://pdxruby.org/"&gt;Portland Ruby Brigade&lt;/a&gt; meetup mentioned using a sun riser.  Being originally from the Chicago, and having lived in Boulder and Manhattan I never had this problem before.  If you google "sunriser lamps" you will find a variety of solutions, many of which I found to be either very ugly or so proprietary that finding bulb replacements would have been a pain in the ass.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, we made our own, and here are the components needed for the hack:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.amazon.com/dp/B0040718V4/?tag=noconf-20"&gt;Leviton LT113-10W 1000-Watt Advanced Digital Plug-In Timer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.schoolhouseelectric.com/lighting-and-hardware/lamps/table-lamps/ion-lamp.html"&gt;Ion Lamp from School House Electric&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.schoolhouseelectric.com/lighting-and-hardware/light-bulbs/g40-frosted-globe.html"&gt;G40 100 Watt Frosted Globe Bulb&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The final product.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/images/posts/SunriserLamp.JPG" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So far I had a significant improvement in waking up more energized and ready to start the day.  As soon as my alarm goes off, I wake up and I am blasted with a nice soft light.  Of course this is no where near the soft sun light wakeup we had in Boulder, however, it feels much better than the constant gray each morning.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;P.S. I fucking love Portland.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Who's Online At 2am?</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/2013/01/01/who-is-online-at-2am/"/>
    <id>/2013/01/01/who-is-online-at-2am/</id>
    <published>2013-01-01T00:00:00-08:00</published>
    <updated>2013-01-01T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Hough</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;There are an endless number of posts out there giving their perspective on what it takes to be an entrepreneur, how to run a startup, how to succeed, and all of that crap we heard from Tony Robbins.  Once you announce you’re doing something in the...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;There are an endless number of posts out there giving their perspective on what it takes to be an entrepreneur, how to run a startup, how to succeed, and all of that crap we heard from Tony Robbins.&amp;nbsp; Once you announce you&amp;rsquo;re doing something in the tech world, &amp;nbsp;the hangers come out of the woodwork from all around you.&amp;nbsp; The hardest to avoid are your close friends and family. I have never had a problem separating business from my personal life, and after a recent experience with a close friend and family member, I wanted to outline our world. This is a blog post about being deep in the mud taking grenades that we could point our close friends and family members to before they begin working on their "this could be the next Facebook" idea.&amp;nbsp; If you have read this far, you must think you have the balls to try something new and&amp;nbsp;succeed.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;p&gt;First before reading anything farther, I want you to &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://youtu.be/lsSC2vx7zFQ"&gt;watch this video&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure class="bt-video-container" style="padding-bottom:75.00%"&gt;&lt;a class="youtube" href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lsSC2vx7zFQ" data-videoid="lsSC2vx7zFQ" data-width="480" data-height="360"&gt;YouTube Video&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of my favorite lines from this clip is &amp;ldquo;I am here to tell you that most of you want to be successful, but you don&amp;rsquo;t want it bad, you just kinda want it.&amp;rdquo;&amp;nbsp; Success is earned.&amp;nbsp; You have to want it bad, each and every minute of every day.&amp;nbsp; In some cases it&amp;rsquo;s the only reason you may be alive today.&amp;nbsp; You WILL NOT SLEEP.&amp;nbsp; If this bothers you, turn around and run away. Let&amp;rsquo;s be honest, this bus ride is not for everyone.&amp;nbsp; At the end of the day, I am ok with that.&amp;nbsp; We live in one of the greatest countries in the world, and if you want it, you can go out and get it.&amp;nbsp; It will not be easy, and most fail in the process.&amp;nbsp; I am tired of the people who look at the person driving the Bentley and saying, &amp;ldquo;oh he or she must be cheating, must be a trust fund kid, etc.&amp;rdquo; Who fucking cares? Why do you care? My father always taught me to work as hard as I could at everything I set out to do, regardless of what others thought.&amp;nbsp; If they are in your way, run them over, not everyone is meant to sit at same table in your house.&amp;nbsp; You get to choose who those close advisors are. Make sure you pick wisely.&amp;nbsp; You may be reading this and thinking &amp;ldquo;Chris only cares about money!&amp;rdquo;&amp;nbsp; If you are thinking this, than stop reading this, find something better to do with your time.&amp;nbsp; It&amp;rsquo;s not about money, it&amp;rsquo;s about enjoying the journey, the stress, the sacrifice, the time, it&amp;rsquo;s about not sleeping. I recently watched this &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://youtu.be/UxjCzSP30wM"&gt;video about a bad ass named Kai Greene&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure class="bt-video-container" style="padding-bottom:75.00%"&gt;&lt;a class="youtube" href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UxjCzSP30wM" data-videoid="UxjCzSP30wM" data-width="480" data-height="360"&gt;YouTube Video&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of his messages, blew me away.&amp;nbsp; &amp;ldquo;What is IT? That other people have that other people seemingly don&amp;rsquo;t.&amp;rdquo;&amp;nbsp; I had to pause to think about this myself.&amp;nbsp; I am not sure I even know the answer. I hope I will in time. Until that day, I will keep my head down, avoiding the grenades and fighting as hard as I can. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So if this vision still means something, and you are not too scared, let me give you a few tips.&amp;nbsp; I have always been a huge believer in what you feed your mind defines where you will go.&amp;nbsp; This list is not comprehensive. I am sure there a ton of important links I am leaving off, but these links mean the most to me. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Listen&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://thisweekinstartups.com/"&gt;This Week in Startups&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://thisweekin.com/thisweekin-venture-capital/"&gt;This Week in Venture Capital&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/itunes-u/entrepreneurial-thought-leaders/id384233886"&gt;Entrepreneurial Thought Leaders by Stanford eCorner&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://foundation.kr/"&gt;Foundation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://news.ycombinator.com/"&gt;Hacker News&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.paulgraham.com/articles.html"&gt;Paul Graham Essays&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.bothsidesofthetable.com/"&gt;Both Sides of the Table&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="n%200307887898"&gt;The Lean Startup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="n%200470929839"&gt;Do More Faster&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="n%200470929820"&gt;Venture Deals&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learn to Code&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://codeschool.zferral.com/l/98/71262"&gt;Codeschool&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://teamtreehouse.com/"&gt;Treehouse&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.codecademy.com/"&gt;Codeacademy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;To the family members, friends, and inquiring contacts I forward this to: Before you present your next greatest idea you thought of in the bathroom, ask yourself how bad do you want it? Have you done your homework? It&amp;rsquo;s not impossible to learn to code. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Are you online at 2am? &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you can check these off, let&amp;rsquo;s meet, if not, remember I am taking grenades in the trenches and may not have the time to hold your hand or draw you a visual diagram.&amp;nbsp; Don&amp;rsquo;t be offended. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The road to the top is paved with bodies. &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cheers.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Hough Eggnog Martini</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/2012/12/01/hough-eggnog-martini/"/>
    <id>/2012/12/01/hough-eggnog-martini/</id>
    <published>2012-12-01T00:00:00-08:00</published>
    <updated>2012-12-01T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Hough</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;If you are looking for a killer holiday cocktail, give this a try!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/images/posts/EggnogMartini-5f2f1391.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;Oberweis Eggnog: 1.5-2&lt;br&gt;Stoli Vanilla: 1.5-2&lt;br&gt;Disaronno Amaretto: 1-1.5&lt;br&gt;Godiva Dark Chocolate: 1-1.5&lt;br&gt;Godiva White Chocolate: 1-1.5&lt;br&gt;Nutmeg&lt;br&gt;*can also add vanilla extract to the shaker for an extra...</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;If you are looking for a killer holiday cocktail, give this a try!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/images/posts/EggnogMartini-5f2f1391.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Oberweis Eggnog: 1.5-2&lt;br /&gt;Stoli Vanilla: 1.5-2&lt;br /&gt;Disaronno Amaretto: 1-1.5&lt;br /&gt;Godiva Dark Chocolate: 1-1.5&lt;br /&gt;Godiva White Chocolate: 1-1.5&lt;br /&gt;Nutmeg&lt;br /&gt;*can also add vanilla extract to the shaker for an extra vanilla taste*#s are the measurements in a full size bar shot glass&lt;p&gt;Over the holidays I modified this into an outstanding blend, instead of using a martini glass I used the following:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Filled a low ball crystal glass half way with Oberweis Eggnog&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Prepped the Large Martini Shaker with Ice&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Poured the glass of eggnog into the shaker&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;add 2-2.5 shots full of Stoli Vanilla&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;add 2-2.5 shots full of Godiva Dark Chocolate Liquor&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;add 2-2.5 shots full of Godiva White Chocolate Liquor&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;add 1 shot of Disaronno Amaretto&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;add a splash of vanilla extract&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;shake to blend all of the contents&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;pour back into the glass&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;sprinkle the top of the drink with nutmeg covering 70-90% of the top&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Enjoy.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;The key to the mix is the amount of eggnog, the less you use the more booze you will taste. Its a fine balance, but I found that using at least 5-7shots of eggnog blended well and practically eliminated the taste of any alcohol.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Programmers Are Fat</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/2012/09/16/programmers-are-fat/"/>
    <id>/2012/09/16/programmers-are-fat/</id>
    <published>2012-09-16T00:00:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2012-09-16T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Hough</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;If you’ve arrived at my post angry and pissed off about the title, welcome.  It was sensational, now I hope you stick around to read the rest of my thoughts.  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/images/posts/ProgrammersAreFat.JPG"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have battled my weight throughout my entire human existence.  The battle has been difficult...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;ve arrived at my post angry and pissed off about the title, welcome.&amp;nbsp; It was sensational, now I hope you stick around to read the rest of my thoughts. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/images/posts/ProgrammersAreFat.JPG" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have battled my weight throughout my entire human existence.&amp;nbsp; The battle has been difficult, long, and I usually lose everything but the weight. Let&amp;rsquo;s face it - when you are writing code, creating a new design, a digital piece of art, or working on your next startup business objectives, you are usually sitting on your ass.&amp;nbsp; The latest craze is standing desks, but they really do not solve the problem.&amp;nbsp; The underlying problem is inactivity. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I put a post up on facebook that created a bit of a stir when I stated that if you are not making fitness a priority in your life alongside your startup, code, and design you are doing it wrong.&amp;nbsp; I stand by this statement.&amp;nbsp; I love to eat, and the choices I have made increased the size of my ass past the point that I consider acceptable. This may sound a bit vain, and it is.&amp;nbsp; While we are busy solving problems or creating the next facebook our bodies are slowly breaking down.&amp;nbsp; Why are we so bad at seeing this problem before it becomes harder and harder to solve?&amp;nbsp; Is it something we choose to ignore and hide behind the &amp;ldquo;geek&amp;rdquo; cloak? &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fitness is not hard.&amp;nbsp; Yes it is far easier if you live in communities like Boulder or Portland, but one could argue you can go for a jog anywhere.&amp;nbsp; I believe that being fit has to be a top priority.&amp;nbsp; When you are at your peak, your mind is clear and ready to battle.&amp;nbsp; I like to think of my brain as a well tooled machine, and the type of fuel I choose can either increase performance or hinder it. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After two weeks of regular workouts including multiple doubles, I am openly committing to getting back on the fitness horse.&amp;nbsp; I wasted too much time in NYC getting to where I am today, essentially erasing all of the progress I made in Boulder.&amp;nbsp; In Portland, I am committing myself once again to the initiative I had in Boulder.&amp;nbsp; I believe that having a body tuned like Ferrari is not a bad thing.&amp;nbsp; It is possible, and in fact our duty.&amp;nbsp; We work hard to create the best software, the best piece of art, why not view our bodies the same way? Why sacrifice ourselves in the process?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I know my hardest challenge is food.&amp;nbsp; Many of you have the same struggle. I am not talking about GMOs, rather just plain heavy foods.&amp;nbsp; I grew up in the Midwest, the land of cheeseburgers and sausages and I learned how to eat.&amp;nbsp; I&amp;rsquo;m conditioned to eat more than I need in a single meal. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This message is not meant to convince you. Make your own choice.&amp;nbsp; Yes, everyone has different circumstances that may make fitness harder or easier, but tell me when fitness has caused a detriment in someone&amp;rsquo;s life.&amp;nbsp; Let&amp;rsquo;s be honest, most people are fat, or overweight in some way.&amp;nbsp; We have grown to accept this reality to the point where the person of normal weight gets judged like they are abnormal. &amp;nbsp; What is wrong with us?&amp;nbsp; Now, I am not Tony Robbins, and I will never claim to be like him.&amp;nbsp; I state my opinions, and I will tell you to &amp;ldquo;Fix your shit!&amp;rdquo;&amp;nbsp; Not every kid is meant to get a trophy, so I am sorry if I sound tough when I say that it&amp;rsquo;s our responsibilities to fix our fat asses. No one else&amp;rsquo;s. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I am publicly committing to this renewed objective in my life.&amp;nbsp; I have not forgotten about it.&amp;nbsp; After spending time in Boulder, where I lived the lightest in my life, I am ready to feel that way again.&amp;nbsp; It feels great.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the end of the day, you will make your own decisions.&amp;nbsp; These decisions will increase your waist line or decrease it.&amp;nbsp; Do not hide behind the geek cloak. It&amp;rsquo;s being a geek that makes you overweight, it&amp;rsquo;s your life choices. So join me and put down that Mt. Dew.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This photo starts month 1 @ 205lbs. &amp;nbsp;My goal 165.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Since We Made It Here We Can Make It Anywhere</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/2012/07/24/since-we-made-it-here-we-can-make-it-anywhere/"/>
    <id>/2012/07/24/since-we-made-it-here-we-can-make-it-anywhere/</id>
    <published>2012-07-24T00:00:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2012-07-24T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Hough</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;After nearly two years in NYC our time has finally come to an end.  During this time we have been all over the city soaking in everything it has to offer.  As we reflect on our time there, we realize just how much we have accomplished and how thankful...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;After nearly two years in NYC our time has finally come to an end.&amp;nbsp; During this time we have been all over the city soaking in everything it has to offer.&amp;nbsp; As we reflect on our time there, we realize just how much we have accomplished and how thankful we are to have had the chance to experience it first hand. New York is a fascinating place filled with big dreams, and even bigger egos.&amp;nbsp; You have to have guts to survive here, and if you have never lived in a major city, amateurs will get eaten alive rapidly.&amp;nbsp; We were lucky enough to have a corporation move us to try it out and living at 83rd and Columbus on the Upper West Side next to the park definitely made things easier.&amp;nbsp; Numerous songs have been written about each of the five boroughs, but this is our take on the experiences we shared.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/images/posts/since-we-made-it-here-we-can-make-it-anywhere-ILoveYouVan.JPG" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s start with the food.&amp;nbsp; With all the cultures of the world blending together it kinda feels like going around the world in Epcot Center, Disney World, but it&amp;rsquo;s the real deal.&amp;nbsp; NYC definitely has the most international feel out of any U.S. city we have lived in.&amp;nbsp; Some of our favorite places include: Cafe Frida {Mexican}, Jacob&amp;rsquo;s Pickles {American heritage} Tacombi {Mexican}, Russ and Daughters {Jewish Deli}, Katz Deli {Jewish Deli}, Sarabeth&amp;rsquo;s {American}, The Spotted Big {British Gastropub}, The Breslin {British Gastropub}, Nobu {Japanese}, Quality Meats {Steakhouse}, Korzo Haus {Czech}, and Keste {Neapolitan Pizza}.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/images/posts/since-we-made-it-here-we-can-make-it-anywhere-table.JPG" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When we not getting fat out on the town, we stocked up on ingredients at some of our favorite food purveyors: Dickson&amp;rsquo;s Farmstand {butcher},&amp;nbsp; Lucy&amp;rsquo;s Whey {artisan cheeses}, Jacques Torres Chocolate, The Lobster Pound, Amy&amp;rsquo;s Bread, and the Union Square Green Market.&amp;nbsp; Although our kitchen would most likely fit in your bathroom, it was actually quite large for NYC city standards.&amp;nbsp; We took advantage of our &amp;ldquo;enormous space&amp;rdquo; as one of the very few families who actually took the time to cook for ourselves. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/images/posts/since-we-made-it-here-we-can-make-it-anywhere-Painting.JPG" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Outside of filling our stomachs, we loved visiting the MOMA, the Met, the Guggenheim, and the Museum of Natural History.&amp;nbsp; Even though we did not have kids, we loved geeking out on the dinosaur bones.&amp;nbsp; Getting to eat lunch regularly&amp;nbsp; on The Highline was relaxing during long summer days.&amp;nbsp; Watching the Macy&amp;rsquo;s Thanksgiving Day Parade was a long time childhood dream, and going to the balloon filling party the night before outside our door made it even more special.&amp;nbsp; We also did a lot of touristy things such as visiting The Statue of Liberty and Ellis Island.&amp;nbsp; Best of all, dragging Kathryn to see the ball drop on New Years Eve freezing, standing on a pizza box to stay warm was hysterical. She hated every minute up until the last 10 seconds. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/images/posts/since-we-made-it-here-we-can-make-it-anywhere-parade.JPG" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Together, all of these events added up to be a life changing experience that we would not trade for the world. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/images/posts/since-we-made-it-here-we-can-make-it-anywhere-subway.JPG" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;By Kathryn...&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For me, living and working in the city was a victory lap to conclude a race that I started ten years before. When I graduated from high school, my only objective was to get the hell out of my small town and do something amazing. I took off for New York after I was accepted to New School University, but I wasn&amp;rsquo;t ready for the path that would be set before me. I returned back to Maine to finish my degree after only three semesters, feeling deflated about my whole experience. When the opportunity arose to return to the city to finish what I started many years ago, I know that I had to give it one more shot.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s funny how life will give you what you want, but not all at the same time. When I was 18 years old, I felt entitled to a big cushy job where I could be paid enough to make the city my own, while doing what I love. In my second go around, I got exactly that. This time, I had the privilege of making a life with someone that I love.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;New York will always hold a special place in my heart. Chris and I got married here. We got our marriage license at NYC City Hall. I took him to the Metropolitan Opera at Lincoln Center for his birthday. We held hands and went ice skating in Rockefeller Center. We spent Christmas Day walking down 5th avenue and catching the last glimpses of the famous holiday windows. We also spent many hours running around the Central Park loop, dreaming of the life that we were just starting to build together. I&amp;rsquo;m glad I never achieved my dreams in my first NYC journey. I learned that it&amp;rsquo;s more fun with someone to share it with.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/images/posts/since-we-made-it-here-we-can-make-it-anywhere-IrishPub.JPG" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;By Chris...&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you know me, you know I like to &amp;ldquo;rant&amp;rdquo; at times.&amp;nbsp; I have always believed that being honest doesn&amp;rsquo;t waste time, however, I have made a promise to myself recently to tailor the message to the desired audience.&amp;nbsp; With that said, Manhattan was a journey back to a major city for me, it was nothing new.&amp;nbsp; I grew up in and around Chicago so I knew what to expect, both the good and the bad.&amp;nbsp; When I left Chicago for Boulder, Colorado I never imagined heading back East ever.&amp;nbsp; I love my wife and when her work came calling &amp;nbsp; what was a good man to do? I had to go.&amp;nbsp; I buckled up and dove in head first selling what I had in Boulder and headed back into the depths of hell I ran so far away from. This time around, however, I learned more about me, and a better understanding of why I left Chicago for Boulder in first place. &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have come to learn that people like what they like and that even though there are parts of the island that I love, I would rather not listen to John Lock and get off for good. It&amp;rsquo;s just not for me.&amp;nbsp; NYC taught me to appreciate nature, more so, than I have ever had before.&amp;nbsp; People that say oh get on a train and just head North to the mountains have either never lived here or didn&amp;rsquo;t have a full time job.&amp;nbsp; I like space, the smell of trees after a morning rain, snow and the people who love it when it falls in buckets, but most importantly peace and quiet.&amp;nbsp; Silence is impossible in NYC.&amp;nbsp; No matter what time of day or night there is just noise, everywhere.&amp;nbsp; NYC has amazing food, just like Chicago, but I loved the farmer&amp;rsquo;s markets of Boulder, not only how easy and pleasant the experiences there were, but the cost.&amp;nbsp; They were far&amp;nbsp; cheaper.&amp;nbsp; The hardest part of the East for me was being a geek.&amp;nbsp; Geeks here are second class citizens.&amp;nbsp; We are not the coolest thing in town, finance and fashion are.&amp;nbsp; I love my t-shirts, I love flannels and normal everyday clothes but most importantly I value my work more than how I dress.&amp;nbsp; I have said the East goes out of it&amp;rsquo;s way to make sure the socioeconomic class system of our country stays in place.&amp;nbsp; Experiencing this first hand was quite alarming and far worse than Chicago.&amp;nbsp; I am a capitalist but I believe in helping anyone in business, not just my set of elite friends that I went to Harvard with who all wear the same polo shirt.&amp;nbsp; Out West there is a sense of community values, where geeks in a coffee shop like Atlas Purveyors could raise their hand with CSS questions and get answers.&amp;nbsp; Not from google, but from people who actually write code and design everyday.&amp;nbsp; The Western geeks are not jailed to co-working spaces, private clubs, or meetups that always cost money.&amp;nbsp; Is NYC technology hot, yes, but I believe you can start a tech startup anywhere nowadays.&amp;nbsp; Most importantly, if you have a solid product, something worth buying, money will find you.&amp;nbsp; In Chicago I almost left code to be a trader and I have seen first hand how the markets work, it&amp;rsquo;s actually a hobby I hope to pursue further one day.&amp;nbsp; There are always winners and losers in every market and you do not need to live in a certain city to have your business be a winner.&amp;nbsp; This may all sound like a rant, and yes a tid bit on the negative side, but not all of my time here was like jail. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Kathryn and I were married here, in Queens actually, something I could have never planned.&amp;nbsp; NYC taught me to appreciate automation, to be efficient with my time, and to focus on what gives me the best ROI, not only in business, but in life.&amp;nbsp; The times that Kathryn and I shared here make me smile, especially the art museums.&amp;nbsp; Since part of Kathryn&amp;rsquo;s family is from the East I have been lucky enough to travel to Maine.&amp;nbsp; To eat home made lobster roll sandwiches, to smell the ocean, and smell the salt water smashing the Northeastern coast.&amp;nbsp; Recently we visited her friend in rural Maine where I had the chance to eat smores, which I hadn&amp;rsquo;t had since I was a little kid.&amp;nbsp; Most importantly though, I was able to see the stars.&amp;nbsp; I believe that too many people have forgotten what stars actually look like, and how small they make you feel.&amp;nbsp; At the end of the day, NYC has taught me to appreciate the finite amount of time we all have in this world.&amp;nbsp; Who we chose to spend it with, what we chose to work on, where we chose to visit all take from the fixed pool of minutes we have.&amp;nbsp; I am thankful for my experiences here, but I more thankful for getting to experience them with the love of my life.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/images/posts/since-we-made-it-here-we-can-make-it-anywhere-XMASTree.JPG" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bye Bye NYC...&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Houghs are leaving Manhattan on the next big adventure of our lives together.&amp;nbsp; No we are not broadcasting where, and if you know already, consider yourself a member of the VIP Club Hough where the best underground house and techno is played 24/7.&amp;nbsp; As one of our good friends would like to say &amp;ldquo;oooh maan, it&amp;rsquo;s time to partay..&amp;rdquo;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/images/posts/since-we-made-it-here-we-can-make-it-anywhere-liberty.JPG" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Thank you Gotham.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Reason Season Lifetime</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/2012/04/29/reason-season-lifetime/"/>
    <id>/2012/04/29/reason-season-lifetime/</id>
    <published>2012-04-29T00:00:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2012-04-29T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Hough</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Recently I have been pondering real value as it relates to startups.  What are startups actually producing?  How long will these technologies last?  I wanted to take one of my favorite quotations and wrap it around topics that we startup geeks and...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Recently I have been pondering real value as it relates to startups.&amp;nbsp; What are startups actually producing?&amp;nbsp; How long will these technologies last?&amp;nbsp; I wanted to take one of my favorite quotations and wrap it around topics that we startup geeks and entrepreneurs would love. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;p&gt;Every day there are more and more incubators coming online and more and more new startups being released into the wild.&amp;nbsp; Without sounding too cryptic, I often ask myself what value are many of these companies adding? Do they care?&amp;nbsp; The companies of our parents and grandparents were built to last for generations. I question how long many of the startup companies today will be around. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Building a company is tough. It takes more than just words.&amp;nbsp; I am no longer interested in bragging about what I am working on. I would rather take that time to produce and let my work speak for itself.&amp;nbsp; I believe in building brands that last the test of time.&amp;nbsp; The great companies of today were not successes overnight and they lasted generations because they continued to focus on innovation, new products, and a solid brand.&amp;nbsp; I love technology but I truly detest how short sighted many people are.&amp;nbsp; If you ask me, wasting my time building a company to flip is no different than flipping condos.&amp;nbsp; I would rather set out to disrupt an industry and stick with it until all options have been exhausted.&amp;nbsp; Don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong: I am not saying to put all of your eggs in one basket. An average type-A person can have a ton of complex investments running concurrently.&amp;nbsp; I am saying I prefer to build something of value.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I look at a few of my favorite brands outside of technology sector like Dewalt, Berkshire Hathaway, Mercedes, or even Katz Deli in NYC, they have lasted for generations.&amp;nbsp; They are places were fathers and daughters work together and they have a respected, sought after culture. They are recognized globally, and they provide real value. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I work on a product, I ask myself which category I want my company to fall into: Reason, Season, or Lifetime.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Reason companies are often called &amp;ldquo;Feature&amp;rdquo; companies, designed around a single task, or small set of tasks, waiting to get acquired.&amp;nbsp; They may or may not shoot for hockey stick like growth, but they will not last on their own. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Season companies come into the markets, disrupt a sector, usually have hockey stick like growth, than either fizzle out or get acquired for a much cheaper valuation. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lifetime based companies last the test of time.&amp;nbsp; They represent a set of products, or entire platform, may or may not have venture capital, and may be publicly traded.&amp;nbsp; Another key factor in determining where a company falls is just how much impact they will have to the world.&amp;nbsp; Easier said than done.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I was once told that how wealthy you are can be determined by the following formula: How long can your family, your children, your children's&amp;lsquo; children and so on live at the same level as you today, without working.&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;I hope to build products and companies that last so that when I kick the bucket, I actually accomplished something.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re building a technology company, build a strong foundation.&amp;nbsp; Focus on your vision, your product, where you are going, and ignore the fucking scenesters.&amp;nbsp; Build a strong advisory board of close friends, not just people who hang on you.&amp;nbsp; You will work a good portion of your life so make sure it happens in the location you want it to, not where someone else or incubator tells you to.&amp;nbsp; Money will flow to where it&amp;rsquo;s replicated the easiest, and even in these markets many of my Chicago trader friends are killing it for this exact reason.&amp;nbsp; You can get capital outside of the valley or NYC if just work your ass off.&amp;nbsp; Most of what I have said isn&amp;rsquo;t news, it&amp;rsquo;s a conversation I have been having in my head.&amp;nbsp; It&amp;rsquo;s my beliefs on business on paper.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Am I being too traditional with my thinking? Is this just not possible in technology?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of my favorite sayings from an unknown author:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;People come into your life for a&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;REASON&lt;/strong&gt;, a &lt;strong&gt;SEASON&lt;/strong&gt; or a &lt;strong&gt;LIFETIME&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;When you know which one it is, you will know what to do for that person. &amp;nbsp;When someone is in your life for a &lt;strong&gt;REASON&lt;/strong&gt;, it is usually to meet a need you have expressed. They have come to assist you through a difficulty, to provide you with guidance and support, to aid you physically, emotionally or spiritually. They may seem like a godsend and they are. &amp;nbsp;They are there for the reason you need them to be. Then, without any wrongdoing on anyone's part or at an inconvenient time, this person or you will say or do something to bring the relationship to an end. Sometimes they die. Sometimes they walk away. Sometimes they act up and force you to take a stand. &amp;nbsp;What we must realize is that our need has been met, our desire fulfilled, their work is done. The prayer you sent up has been answered and now it is time to move on.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Some people come into your life for a &lt;strong&gt;SEASON&lt;/strong&gt;, because your turn has come to share, grow or learn. They bring you an experience of peace or make youlaugh. They may teach you something you have never done. They usually give you an unbelievable amount of joy. Believe it, it is real.&amp;nbsp;Yet only for a season. &amp;nbsp;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LIFETIME&lt;/strong&gt; relationships teach you lifetime lessons, things you must build upon in order to have a solid emotional foundation. Your job is to accept the lesson, love the person and put what you have learned to use in all other relationships and areas of your life. &amp;nbsp;Lifetime relationships can run continuously, or for many, on again, off again. &amp;nbsp;Your job is to also accept that life may have its ebbs and flows, but time and distance apart does not have to define a relationship.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;footer&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unknown&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/footer&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/images/posts/reason-season-lifetime-2e3dd6cd.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Hough Fat Kid Burgers</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/2012/04/29/hough-fat-kid-burgers/"/>
    <id>/2012/04/29/hough-fat-kid-burgers/</id>
    <published>2012-04-29T00:00:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2012-04-29T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Hough</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;If you’re looking for an outstanding “FAT KID” burger recipe this summer, look no further. I was hesitant to share this family secret but I am curious as to what others could do building off of it.  This recipe makes close to 20 1lb burgers depending...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re looking for an outstanding &amp;ldquo;FAT KID&amp;rdquo; burger recipe this summer, look no further. I was hesitant to share this family secret but I am curious as to what others could do building off of it.&amp;nbsp; This recipe makes close to 20 1lb burgers depending on how big you make each one. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/images/posts/hough-fat-kid-burgers-50b9a7ce.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;7 lbs of 85% lean burger meat.&amp;nbsp; Trust me you need the fat, do not get the extra lean kind.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;4 spicy italian pork sausages.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;3 diced jalape&amp;ntilde;os.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;1 diced red onion.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;3/4 stick of Irish Gold garlic herb butter.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Plenty of garlic powder, and if you have fresh cut cloves toss them in too.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;A few pinches of sea salt.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Plenty of ground pepper.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;4 free range eggs.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Shredded jalape&amp;ntilde;o jack cheese, the more the merrier. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;20oz can of Guinness.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mix all of that together until it&amp;rsquo;s a consistent near solid sticky bowl of meat, than start making patties.&amp;nbsp; Each of the burgers weighs in around 1lb or around the size of a fist. Lay each patty on a cookie sheet covered with tin foil and cover each of them with a thin layer of italian bread crumbs. Now you&amp;rsquo;re ready for the grill.&amp;nbsp; Depending on how well you like your burgers cooked, I usually keep them on the grill for a total of 6-8 minutes, flipping them for 3-4 minutes on each side.&amp;nbsp; Add 2 additional slices of jalape&amp;ntilde;o jack cheese on the second flip to kick it up a notch.&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pairs well with Guinness! &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hope you enjoy this recipe! If you take a stab at it or modify it, let me know how it goes.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Every Kid Gets A Trophy</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/2012/04/25/every-kid-gets-a-trophy/"/>
    <id>/2012/04/25/every-kid-gets-a-trophy/</id>
    <published>2012-04-25T00:00:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2012-04-25T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Hough</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have been working as a code monkey ever since I left college.  I learn visually but can handle straight text when I need to, and I would like to think that I am not design inept. &lt;!--more--&gt;A hefty goal of mine this year is to work hard to master &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.ruby-lang.org/en/"&gt;Ruby&lt;/a&gt; and the...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have been working as a code monkey ever since I left college.&amp;nbsp; I learn visually but can handle straight text when I need to, and I would like to think that I am not design inept.&amp;nbsp;&lt;!--more--&gt;A hefty goal of mine this year is to work hard to master &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.ruby-lang.org/en/"&gt;Ruby&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://rubyonrails.org/"&gt;Ruby on Rails&lt;/a&gt; framework.&amp;nbsp; My traditional experience told me to find a class first, however, after listening to numerous recommendations from &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.thisweekinstartups.com/"&gt;This Week in Startups&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://thisweekin.com/thisweekin-web/"&gt;This Week in Web Design&lt;/a&gt; I started out online.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/images/posts/every-kid-gets-a-trophy-5ac15a7c.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For this experiment I pretended to start from scratch as though I had no prior programming or design experience.&amp;nbsp; I knew I would tackle more than just Ruby classes, but I wanted to experience all of it first hand. I started with &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.codeschool.com/"&gt;Code School&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://teamtreehouse.com/"&gt;Treehouse&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.codecademy.com/"&gt;Code School&lt;/a&gt;. I know there are quite a few out there but I feel these three cover a good number of core competencies. Or, at least they claim to. I also wanted to test the theory I have been hearing others say that &amp;ldquo;college is just not required anymore.&amp;rdquo;&amp;nbsp; I started this experiment at the first of the year, with the initial hypothesis that &amp;ldquo;college is necessary for coding and design.&amp;rdquo;&amp;nbsp; Let me break down each of the three online options I used.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.codecademy.com/"&gt;Codecademy&lt;/a&gt; is the cheapest of the three. It&amp;rsquo;s free. It also has the most functional design.&amp;nbsp; Some users may be turned off by this, the same way they would be opening a math book.&amp;nbsp; It&amp;rsquo;s primary focus is javascript, but they recently started offering some css and html courses.&amp;nbsp; Being a coder, I enjoyed the code samples and the logical progression through the course.&amp;nbsp; There wasn&amp;rsquo;t any fluff. No videos.&amp;nbsp; No music.&amp;nbsp; Just code.&amp;nbsp; If you are setting out to learn javascript and jquery I would advise you to take every course available here first.&amp;nbsp; You will learn javascript, not every piece of it, but you will get a solid base.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://teamtreehouse.com/"&gt;Treehouse&lt;/a&gt; definitely has the most &amp;ldquo;fluff&amp;rdquo; out of the three and by far the most content, however, it is also the most expensive.&amp;nbsp; If you are truly new to technology you will enjoy the videos, music, and multiple choice tests.&amp;nbsp; The lack of true coding examples and tests keeps me from recommending it ahead of &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.codeschool.com/"&gt;Code School&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; Overall I would say &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://teamtreehouse.com/"&gt;Treehouse&lt;/a&gt; would be best for designers transitioning into coding, but it will not in it&amp;rsquo;s current state give you all of the necessary tools to complete that transition. You will need the other two for sure.&amp;nbsp; In terms of the design basics like layout or color theory I thought the topics were thoroughly covered. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.codeschool.com/"&gt;Code School&lt;/a&gt; won me over completely the moment I opened the &amp;ldquo;Try Ruby&amp;rdquo; course.&amp;nbsp; The site has an excellent blend between videos, music, and writing code.&amp;nbsp; While it does not have as much content as &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://teamtreehouse.com/"&gt;Treehouse&lt;/a&gt;, I have to say that &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.codeschool.com/"&gt;Code School&lt;/a&gt; takes a more in depth approach to learning.&amp;nbsp; Outside of their courses they also have hours of video content available on a variety of subjects.&amp;nbsp; If you ask me, if you are brand new, start with &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.codecademy.com/"&gt;Codecademy&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.codeschool.com/"&gt;Code School&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I would like to think that learning online has come a long way. Sadly, I have to say it still has a way to go before it can replace classroom learning for technical subjects completely.&amp;nbsp; Yes, you learn the basics. However online learning will not give you that in depth perspective, and definitely not the community aspect of working along side your peers in the same room. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the end of the day I ended up signing up for a course at &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.scps.nyu.edu/course-detail/INFO1-CE9970/20121/ruby-on-rails/"&gt;NYU on Ruby on Rails&lt;/a&gt; and I am glad I did.&amp;nbsp; By combining the online courses from &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://codeschool.zferral.com/l/98/71262"&gt;Code School&lt;/a&gt; and the traditional experience in the class room I feel will be able to start building things in Ruby after the course.&amp;nbsp; No, I will not be a pro by any means, but I have the tools to start,&amp;nbsp; and have networked with fellow mentors to keep the learning process going.&amp;nbsp; Networking is not the only area where online learning breaks down.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The biggest problem with online learning is this: every person gets a trophy or a badge, and no one can get a failing grade.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://teamtreehouse.com/"&gt;Treehouse&lt;/a&gt; tests were beyond easy to game, and no matter how many times you failed a question you can just keep guessing until you passed. &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.codecademy.com/"&gt;Codecademy&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.codeschool.com/"&gt;Code School&lt;/a&gt; handled this best by making the user submit code examples to progress to the next session, however, you still have access to google and &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://stackoverflow.com/"&gt;Stack Overflow&lt;/a&gt; to cheat your way through.&amp;nbsp; Let&amp;rsquo;s not pretend people do not cheat.&amp;nbsp; In order for learning to be effective there has to be failing grades, markers to force people to start over.&amp;nbsp; The carrots or badges are great, but what do they truly represent?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Would you hire someone based on the number of badges they have?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I keep hearing people questioning if college is necessary, and backing up those claims with sites like these, or the fact they are already running a startup with only their high school diploma.&amp;nbsp; Still, college degrees are still valid and in many cases required.&amp;nbsp; That&amp;rsquo;s not to say that there are not winning lottery tickets out there who have success, it&amp;rsquo;s not the norm.&amp;nbsp; This is not an attack on them at all.&amp;nbsp; I am happy it worked out for them.&amp;nbsp; To me, it&amp;rsquo;s like taking all of your savings and buying lottery tickets with it. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;School teaches more than coding, it teaches interpersonal skills, communication, time management, and how to interact with others to name a few.&amp;nbsp; My wife and I plan on having a family soon and schooling, especially the type of schooling, is a top most priority.&amp;nbsp; I am often asked what about college as I am the only programmer in my immediate family.&amp;nbsp; Here is where a good blend of reasoning comes in.&amp;nbsp; Does it make sense to buy the lotto ticket and avoid college all together? No.&amp;nbsp; It also does not make sense to stay 100% in the classroom with no real world experience.&amp;nbsp; In my opinion you need a blend.&amp;nbsp; I would advise our children to complete college over the course of 4-6 years blended with coding, online learning, and working at startups full time.&amp;nbsp; People need to know how to talk, how to interact with others, especially members of the opposite sex in the workplace.&amp;nbsp; They need to learn just how bad the &amp;ldquo;brogramming&amp;rdquo; experience really is and why they shouldn&amp;rsquo;t recreate it.&amp;nbsp; Having a broad scope of knowledge across a variety of technical and non-technical subjects helps prevent creating a horse in central park with blinders on.&amp;nbsp; It also, helps them be a better leader and less likely to be taken advantage of by others. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Call me crazy, but school still wins my vote.&amp;nbsp; Until the online sites actually give failing grades and better report card like metrics, they are not going to replace the classroom experience completely.&amp;nbsp; Instead of thinking every kid gets a trophy, maybe we should consider the fact that we are all different.&amp;nbsp; Not everyone will be a coder or designer, just like not everyone can play sports.&amp;nbsp; If you or a child is horrible at baseball, try basketball, try football, or do whatever you feel you can do best.&amp;nbsp; If you&amp;rsquo;re are always awarded trophies and badges you will not know what you are actually proficient at.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>2012 Goals</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/2012/01/12/2012-goals/"/>
    <id>/2012/01/12/2012-goals/</id>
    <published>2012-01-12T00:00:00-08:00</published>
    <updated>2012-01-12T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Hough</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Instead of the plain old yearly goals that everyone outlines for the future, every new year, I started thinking about themes and what means the most to me in 2012.  What can I change now, starting now, today.  I have come to understand and accept my...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Instead of the plain old yearly goals that everyone outlines for the future, every new year, I started thinking about themes and what means the most to me in 2012. &amp;nbsp;What can I change now, starting now, today. &amp;nbsp;I have come to understand and accept my past, learn from it, grow from it, but not let it hold me back. &amp;nbsp;I am not afraid to tell others what I feel, even if it's not what they want to hear. &amp;nbsp;I have grown to accept the fact that pleasing everyone is truly impossible, and being a&amp;nbsp;chameleon is b.s. &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;When you set out to start a company, sail a ship, buy a one way ticket you have to have a set of parameters to guide you, yet, not restrict you so much there are no alternatives. &amp;nbsp;Since I have left Chicago, life has been a roller coaster to say the least. &amp;nbsp;There have been ups and downs, but I still do not regret taking my first steps on the path away from where I grew up. &amp;nbsp;The nervousness has since subsided, but the excitement hasn't. &amp;nbsp;The friends I have met on my journey outside of Chicago have quickly become part of the chosen family I hope to have forever, and the plans I have made with the love of my life Kathryn warm my heart. &amp;nbsp;So what's next? I think of this all the time. &amp;nbsp;Yes, there are many things brewing in the kitchen - have to say this for our stalkers. &amp;nbsp;But focusing on themes, I have locked in three for me:&lt;strong&gt;Think&lt;/strong&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;Create&lt;/strong&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;Act.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;Yes, they are a little broad, but after quite a few sessions on the treadmill I was able to narrow down my focus to these three.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/images/posts/yearlygoals2012-1b04f35d.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Think&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This year I want to dive deeper into&amp;nbsp;Buddhism, learn more about the spiritual journey, it's a piece of me that I have grown to appreciate the more I dive in. &amp;nbsp;Directly related to this spiritual&amp;nbsp;initiative&amp;nbsp;is what I call being more "zen" or the "water flowing through rocks." &amp;nbsp;Working and living in a major city like Chicago or Manhattan, comes with stress, plain and simple. If you have ever lived in a major city, you know what I am referring to. &amp;nbsp;No, I am not going into the rants now, I will save them for later, but they are easy to list. &amp;nbsp;While you can not control others, you have full control over your reactions to others' behaviors or lack there of. &amp;nbsp;I have come to learn and actively practice not letting much get to me. &amp;nbsp;Life is just too short to be stressed right? &amp;nbsp;If you follow me on twitter, you just read this and was like "yeah right" but acknowledge this, there is a big difference between rants {tweets} and the movements you make every day in life just walking down the street, holding the door for your elderly neighbor, and helping a child get a drink off the coffee shop counter.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Create&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I enjoy working in coldfusion, but to be honest. I am creative. &amp;nbsp;I have started learning Ruby and Rails this year and have been focusing more on UIE. &amp;nbsp;As my wife has taken the leap into learning how to code, I will be spending time &amp;nbsp;on a journey I call back to the basics. &amp;nbsp;I am planning on going through the same set of Treehouse tasks she has been going through. &amp;nbsp;I figure a solid refresher, no matter how long you have been coding can't hurt. &amp;nbsp;Plus, there are always things that you have been doing, sometimes for years, incorrectly in terms of coding architecture and principles. &amp;nbsp;I want to write more in 2012, not for you, but for me. &amp;nbsp;While I would welcome an audience to read my craziness, I want to be open with myself, be authentic, and put it out there on paper. &amp;nbsp;Don't care if I get signed for a book. &amp;nbsp;It's for me. Enjoy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Act&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have made a commitment to kill off my fat stomach. &amp;nbsp;No, I do not have body image issues, but health and fitness are huge priorities in my life. &amp;nbsp;I like being tone, fit, and that means it has to go. &amp;nbsp;Luckily we live a very holistic lifestyle and are probably one of the only families who actually cook at home in Manhattan. &amp;nbsp;While I may never get a 6 pack, shedding about ten pounds would make me very happy. &amp;nbsp;Being married to a personal trainer has it's perks and have already put on a significant amount of muscle mass breaking through markers on squats, shoulder presses, and even simple things like dips. &amp;nbsp;Yet, being the type-a person I am, I have quite a ways to go.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I will expand on these as make my way through this year, and to be honest with you, this year's plans already make me beyond excited. &amp;nbsp;What do you think? Think I am crazy? &amp;nbsp;I hope you do. &amp;nbsp;Keep on fighting, keep on learning, keep on kicking ass and taking names.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>I Run 4 The Fuck Yous &amp; Fuck Yeahs!</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/2011/10/23/i-run-for-the-fuck-yous-and-fuck-yeahs/"/>
    <id>/2011/10/23/i-run-for-the-fuck-yous-and-fuck-yeahs/</id>
    <published>2011-10-23T00:00:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2011-10-23T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Hough</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;What do you think of when you run? When you’re busting your ass at the gym? Is it only about losing weight or something more?  My journey to health started a few years ago when I landed in Colorado.  I used to weigh over 200lbs! Yes, I know.  Fat ass...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;What do you think of when you run? When you&amp;rsquo;re busting your ass at the gym? Is it only about losing weight or something more? &amp;nbsp;My journey to health started a few years ago when I landed in Colorado. &amp;nbsp;I used to weigh over 200lbs! Yes, I know. &amp;nbsp;Fat ass! Seriously though, it was pretty disgusting, and if you ever visit Colorado, you&amp;rsquo;ll learn quickly why it&amp;rsquo;s known as the healthiest state in the U.S.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;iframe
      width="500"
      height="281"
      src="http://player.vimeo.com/video/5739058"
      frameborder="0" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen&gt;
      &lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I met my wife she encouraged me to start training, working out for more than just weight loss, and instead focusing on events. &amp;nbsp;Not competing to win, but running to be part of the small percentage of like minded bad asses that swim, bike, run for fun. &amp;nbsp;The same drive and determination to succeed in life easily applies to racing, to exercise, to anything for that matter. &amp;nbsp;After deep periods of reflection in my life I came to discover that I always did everything, every sport, every task, whatever 110%. &amp;nbsp;That means if you sat a bottle of Kettle One in front of me, consider it gone. Type-A people don&amp;rsquo;t fuck around, they don&amp;rsquo;t waste time. &amp;nbsp;They need a mission, a goal to hook on to, to run with, to put that high paced energy into. &amp;nbsp;Often, they choose poorly. &amp;nbsp;I chose to be an athlete.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I first started running, I used to picture all of the people, places, events that pissed me off. &amp;nbsp;You know the ones right? &amp;nbsp;I pictured them as though I was there, tasting the air, feeling the emotions rushing through my veins. In my mind, I was punching that person in the face, standing up in front of haters and screaming fuck you, driving that ferrari 360 modena top down at 150mph. &amp;nbsp;Working out angry solved a problem. It seemed to fill a void. &amp;nbsp;The rush of adrenaline helped kill off the old feelings, the baggage I had been carrying.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As an athlete you can either work out angry or happy. &amp;nbsp;I only knew how to run for the fuck yous. &amp;nbsp;More and more time went by, and I shaved more and more time off my current mile pace as well as built a good amount of new muscle mass, yet, something was missing. &amp;nbsp;I was losing energy. &amp;nbsp;The anger wasn&amp;rsquo;t there anymore. &amp;nbsp;One day running on the treadmill my ipod started blasting &amp;ldquo;I Remember&amp;rdquo;, by Kaskade.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I felt a new rush come over me that I had never felt before. &amp;nbsp;It was pure happiness. &amp;nbsp;I wasn&amp;rsquo;t mad anymore. &amp;nbsp;This newfound energy rushed through my veins even more powerful than when I was angry. I felt lighter, less burdened, and the thoughts rushing through my mind were happy, thankful, filled with joy. &amp;nbsp;I started running for the fuck yeahs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The people, the events, the experiences I am grateful for in life. &amp;nbsp;The times I cried out of joy, the plans I have for the future, the focus I have in my journey of enlightenment. &amp;nbsp;Living. &amp;nbsp;I know nothing is perfect in life, but what I have learned so far, is that being negative, carrying anger, being mad, just wastes time. &amp;nbsp;It brings negative energy into your life and the lives of those around you. &amp;nbsp;Yes, running angry for me served a purpose, a means to purge myself of older lingering feelings, to get rid of fear, to make room for the holes to be filled with light. &amp;nbsp;If you&amp;rsquo;re working out angry, be conscious of these feelings, let them pass, and work towards working out happy. &amp;nbsp;Be yourself, and let these feelings go, move on to better things.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Today is Monday, October 24th 2011, and this is my first ever blog post. &amp;nbsp;If you do not like what I have to say, so be it. &amp;nbsp;Go somewhere else. &amp;nbsp;I don&amp;rsquo;t care if you like it or not, my writing is not for everyone. &amp;nbsp;If you care to share what inspires you to run, I would love to find out. &amp;nbsp;I hope we can inspire each other.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Successful Startup</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/2011/02/05/a-successful-startup-married/"/>
    <id>/2011/02/05/a-successful-startup-married/</id>
    <published>2011-02-05T00:00:00-08:00</published>
    <updated>2011-02-05T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Hough</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It could be argued that finding your business partner is no different than being lucky enough to find the right
 person for you.  I can not begin to share with you, just how many failures I have had at this game, but this
 time I got it right.  In...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It could be argued that finding your business partner is no different than being lucky enough to find the right
 person for you.  I can not begin to share with you, just how many failures I have had at this game, but this
 time I got it right.  In the startup of life I have made one of the best decisions I ever could have made.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/images/posts/Married-704be004.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A letter to our families:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Family and Friends,&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Finding your soulmate in this world is quite a challenge. It’s something that takes time and lots of searching. It also takes a great understanding of who you are, what you want in another person, and where you want to go in this world. The search comes not without diversions and challenges, but in the end, it is one of the most amazing things you can do in this life.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Chris and Kate are very excited to announce a very happy surprise.  We decided to get married! We have been talking about getting married for quite sometime, and we decided not to wait. We met on February 8, 2010 in Boulder, CO, and we were married on February 5, 2011 in Queens, NY.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The whole event was very New York and we did it just like you would expect. Kate is low maintenance (the opposite of a bridezilla) – shebought her wedding dress from Macy’s in Herald Square. We also had our rings handcrafted by an artisan from Massachusetts. We had cakefrom Magnolia Bakery, one of the most famous bakeries in the city!  For the ceremony, we were accompanied by a non-denominational pastorand a witness –that’s it! We are very excited that our lives have brought us together in NYC and we hope to enjoy a few exciting years together as newlyweds before were expand our family.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;We are lucky to have you all as supportive friends and family in just about every time zone.  Because of this, we are going to celebrate our marriage with you all next year, for our first wedding anniversary. We’re planning on making a few stops across the country to celebrate this good news.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;We will be sending announcements to our close friends and family in the coming weeks with more info and pictures.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; Lots of love&lt;/p&gt;&lt;footer&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chris and Kate Hough&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/footer&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Not a day goes by when I am not thankful for have meeting &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/kathrynhough"&gt;KathrynHough&lt;/a&gt;. I love you baby.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Like any true Boulder hippie, I had an amazing pony tail.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
